<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on JS.geek.NZ Bevan Rudge</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on JS.geek.NZ Bevan Rudge</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://js.geek.nz/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Where will your grandkids be 60 years from now?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/where-will-your-grandkids-be-60-years-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/where-will-your-grandkids-be-60-years-now/</guid><description>It is not often I blog off topic, so I hope that you can appreciate how important this is, and spare a few minutes to save your own future, your children's and grandchildren's futures and home planet.
Would you just stand around and watch as your home burned down with your children and pets inside? No? So please don't stand around and watch while we destroy our home planet.</description></item><item><title>"Community Plumbing", Toilet humour and a hilarious video</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/community-plumbing-toilet-humour-and-hilarious-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/community-plumbing-toilet-humour-and-hilarious-video/</guid><description> Is there something wrong with your brand when it reminds people of toilet humour?
The best two minutes of entertainment I've had in months:</description></item><item><title>"Drupal For Education And E-Learning" Book Review</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-education-and-e-learning-book-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-education-and-e-learning-book-review/</guid><description>Drupal for Education and E-learningis a must-have for any teacher, school or education institution considering a new school website, or technology-centric project in the classroom. Whether the reader has heard of Drupal or not, the book provides valuable insights, empowering ideas and simple instructions to help get any teacher or school on their way to having a powerful, useful and valuable learning resource.
read more</description></item><item><title>"Unfortunately, contacts has stopped" on Samsung Galaxy S3</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/unfortunately-contacts-has-stopped-samsung-galaxy-s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/unfortunately-contacts-has-stopped-samsung-galaxy-s3/</guid><description>I have not been able to use the dialer/keypad or log/history in the Phone app on my Samsang Galaxy S3 since an Android upgrade about four months ago. Whenever I opened them I would get the message "Unfortunately, contacts has stopped". And in order to dial numbers I would have to save them as a contact first.
It is a bug in Android that causes certain configurations to have no valid date format, which in turn causes Contacts app to crash this bug.</description></item><item><title>2008 Prediction; (Drupal : websites) == (Linux : webhosts)</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/2008-prediction-drupal-websites-linux-webhosts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/2008-prediction-drupal-websites-linux-webhosts/</guid><description>I have just one simple prediction for Drupal in 2008;
Drupal becomes to websites and the website-producing industry, what Linux is to webservers and the web-hosting industry.
Realistically this will probably take well into 2009 for this to be effective to the extent that linux, but the foundations for this are already laid and I believe that with the current momentum, it's just time before my prediction becomes true.</description></item><item><title>A New Way to Migrate WordPress Content Into Drupal</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/new-way-migrate-wordpress-content-drupal-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/new-way-migrate-wordpress-content-drupal-0/</guid><description>The Donald W. Reynolds Journalism Institute (RJI) is an organization that seeks out and tests innovations in journalism to find the best solutions for use in the real world.
Their new Palantir-developed Drupal website replaces a custom PHP website and two WordPress.com blogs. Part of our assignment involved migrating content from RJI's WordPress blogs into Drupal. Initially, we intended to do this using the WordPress Import module. However WordPress Import is a stand-alone module that does not integrate with CCK fields, meaning that you cannot import WordPress post categories or authors as CCK text or node-reference fields.</description></item><item><title>Accessibility For Humans; Usability Of Websites For Screen Reader Users</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/accessibility-humans-usability-websites-screen-reader-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/accessibility-humans-usability-websites-screen-reader-users/</guid><description>A graph from the article showing disabilities reported: Read the full article I recently read a fascinating survey of 1000 blind and visually impaired internet users. It's a long article but is largely graphs and data tables – so is easily consumed. If you want the short version, check out the comments and conclusion.
The most surprising parts for me were;
Websites that auto-play music (MySpace most notably) are extremely difficult because the sound makes it hard for the user to listen to screen readers.</description></item><item><title>ACLU's "Freedom Files" Season 2</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/aclus-freedom-files-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/aclus-freedom-files-season-2/</guid><description>Many folk don't know that the ACLU has a TV series called "The Freedom Files". Season 2 can be seen on PBS stations throughout the country. Episodes can also be viewed online at aclu.tv which we re-launched for the new season recently.
read more</description></item><item><title>Aight, done</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/aight-done/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/aight-done/</guid><description>I just finished moving all my posts from blogspot to drupal 6 beta 3. Whew...
Now to see about redirecting users from blogspot to here...</description></item><item><title>Air New Zealand is Using Linux</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/air-new-zealand-using-linux-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/air-new-zealand-using-linux-0/</guid><description>Air New Zealand's in-flight entertainment system runs Linux. Unfortunately the layer of software that Air NZ has deployed on top of Linux is buggy and I noticed at least twice in one 3-hour flight that it crashed, causing Linux to reboot. (This is what led me to discover the systems run Linux.)
Watching Linux boot on the seat-back console screen was fun. And it was nice to see Tux the Penguin about the airline.</description></item><item><title>Air New Zealand is Using Linux</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/air-new-zealand-using-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/air-new-zealand-using-linux/</guid><description>Air New Zealand's in-flight entertainment system runs Linux. Unfortunately the layer of software that Air NZ has deployed on top of Linux is buggy and I noticed at least twice in one 3-hour flight that it crashed, causing Linux to reboot. (This is what led me to discover the systems run Linux.)
Watching Linux boot on the seat-back console screen was fun. And it was nice to see Tux the Penguin about the airline.</description></item><item><title>Am I a fanboy?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/am-i-a-fanboy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/am-i-a-fanboy/</guid><description>Apparently I'm an Apple Fanboi. Maybe I am. I don't try to be. Actually I try not to be. Maybe I'm a sucker for shiny gadgets. Worse, perhaps I'm a sucker of good marketing. In any case, I'd like apple-fanbois and critics to know that I &amp;lt;metaphor&amp;gt; keep a lifejacket under my seat in case I need to jump ship &amp;lt;/metaphor&amp;gt;. By that I mean; I am an open source enthusiast.</description></item><item><title>Announcing NZ's first drupal camp: DrupalSouth</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/announcing-nzs-first-drupal-camp-drupalsouth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/announcing-nzs-first-drupal-camp-drupalsouth/</guid><description>Together with some friends and colleagues we have been working hard to organise, finalize and publish details of what will be the two most important days for Drupal in New Zealand:
DrupalSouth: The New Zealand Drupal Event for 2008 DrupalSouth is the New Zealand Drupal Event for 2008. DrupalSouth will bring NZ's Drupal community together for the first nation-wide Drupal event and the first ever Drupal camp in NZ.</description></item><item><title>Applegasmic -- Hot New iPorn!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/applegasmic-hot-new-iporn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/applegasmic-hot-new-iporn/</guid><description>I'm having an applegism. Check out this iPorn:
See the Ad</description></item><item><title>Authenticated Users Do Not Inherit Anonymous Role Permissions</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/authenticated-users-do-not-inherit-anonymous-role-permissions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/authenticated-users-do-not-inherit-anonymous-role-permissions/</guid><description>Contrary to common belief, Drupal's Authenticated user role does not inherit permissions given to the Anonymous user role.
read more</description></item><item><title>Away December 7 to 17</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/away-december-7-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/away-december-7-17/</guid><description>I'm away in Australia visiting family and attending a wedding from Friday 7 December to Monday 17 December. I will have little (if any) internet connectivity while away.
I'm back! Had fun. All family stuff, lot's of driving, some kangaroos and a few beaches.</description></item><item><title>Backcountry ski touring insurance in Canada</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/backcountry-ski-touring-insurance-canada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/backcountry-ski-touring-insurance-canada/</guid><description>I researched and compared travel insurances that include cover for backcountry ski touring for 28 days in Canada for a NZ-resident couple in their thirties. Most travel insurers exclude skiing outside of the ski area, or off-piste. These are the options I found. Most also offer annual options which are comparable to 4-week single trips.
DISCLAIMER: I am not qualified to give financial advice.
Tugo, via Alpine Club of Canada UPDATE For a small claim, Tugo Insurance took 9 months of processing and achieved nothing.</description></item><item><title>Best LOLcat</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/best-lolcat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/best-lolcat/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Best Photos From DrupalCon Paris 2009</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/best-photos-drupalcon-paris-2009/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/best-photos-drupalcon-paris-2009/</guid><description>If you don't want to browse the 2500+ photos from DrupalCon Paris on Flickr, but still want to see some photos, try these sets for the highlights instead;
Bevan's Favorites on Flickr (215 in set) – a selection of highlights from all DrupalCon Paris photos. Elv's DrupalCon Paris 20009 photo set (179 set) Jeff Eaton's photos tagged "DrupalCon" (26 in set) Petro Lozano's Drupal Paris 2009 photo set (94 in set) Bevan's DrupalCon Paris 2009 set (138 in set) Namo's DrupalCon Paris 2009 photo set (85 in set) read more</description></item><item><title>Bring it ON, DrupalcON; People I want to meet</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/bring-it-on-drupalcon-people-i-want-meet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/bring-it-on-drupalcon-people-i-want-meet/</guid><description>[Update: this had the wrong tag to get on Planet Drupal]
I'm really looking forward to DrupalCon Boston 2008. The highlight for me will likely be meeting a bunch of really great people I have come to know, respect and be inspired by;
Everyone at CivicActions; My awesome colleagues and team-mates for the last 6 months. Dries Buytaert; For obvious reasons. Karoly Chx Negyesi; It's been great having your support on SoU.</description></item><item><title>Call for PostgreSQL developers for drupal 6</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/call-postgresql-developers-drupal-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/call-postgresql-developers-drupal-6/</guid><description>For those that don't read the development list; there has been considerable discussion recently (following Khaled's PG vs MySQL benchmarks) about improving PG support in drupal 6.
I haven't followed the whole discussion in detail (so please correct my if I'm wrong or have missed something), but it seems that for PG support to be sustained and/or improve in drupal6, more PG testers and developers with an interest in PG support are needed.</description></item><item><title>Celebrating 2010 &amp;amp; the Achievements of the Drupal Association</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/celebrating-2010-achievements-drupal-association-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/celebrating-2010-achievements-drupal-association-0/</guid><description>2010 has been a big year for the Drupal Association. Early in the year new members were brought on and the Board of Directors saw some changes. But most noteworthy is what the Drupal Association did for the Drupal community;
Drupal.org Redesign Completion Drupal.org has a new look and feel. If you have not seen it (have you been under a rock!?) go check out Drupal.org right now!</description></item><item><title>Censorship quote</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/censorship-quote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/censorship-quote/</guid><description> Not sure where this one came from;
Censorship is the editing of collective human consiousness</description></item><item><title>Changing Young People's Misperceptions about Computer Science</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/changing-young-peoples-misperceptions-about-computer-science-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/changing-young-peoples-misperceptions-about-computer-science-0/</guid><description>A number of recent events – including a recent interview with Tim Bell, creator of Computer Science Unplugged, and the closure of Hagley School's futuristic College of Computing for the 2009 academic year – have motivated me to want to do something about the lack of interest in CSSE (computer science in the broadest sense) and – in particular – the misperceptions young people have about it. I believe it is these misperceptions that results in the lack of interest.</description></item><item><title>Changing Young People's Misperceptions about Computer Science</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/changing-young-peoples-misperceptions-about-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/changing-young-peoples-misperceptions-about-computer-science/</guid><description>A number of recent events – including a recent interview with Tim Bell, creator of Computer Science Unplugged, and the closure of Hagley School's futuristic College of Computing for the 2009 academic year – have motivated me to want to do something about the lack of interest in CSSE (computer science in the broadest sense) and – in particular – the misperceptions young people have about it. I believe it is these misperceptions that results in the lack of interest.</description></item><item><title>Cheap Flights to DrupalAPC via NZ</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/cheap-flights-drupalapc-nz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/cheap-flights-drupalapc-nz/</guid><description>I don't like to advertise, but this might save someone $1000 USD:
If you've been thinking about coming to New Zealand from the US, now is the time to get tickets. Qantas has specials that have cut flight prices by about 50%.
$900-$1000 USD from West Coast USA to AKL, WTN, CHC or Queenstown.
Around $1300 USD from East Coast to AKL, WTN, CHC or Queenstown.
If you're thinking about going to Drupalcon Sydney in May, it may be cheaper to fly via NZ with those specials.</description></item><item><title>CivicActions In Paris!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/civicactions-paris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/civicactions-paris/</guid><description>CivicActions is in Paris, and we are running some great sessions at DrupalCon Paris 2009;
Day 2, Wednesday 2 September; How to contribute to Drupal by Stella Power and Bevan Rudge Day 3, Thursday 3 September; Projets Multilingues, multilingual internationlized projects too! by Doug Green and others. Hosting meetups, camps, and virtual classes: building the community that builds Drupal by Stella Power and others. Day 4, Friday 4 September; jQuery for designers and themers by Bevan Rudge.</description></item><item><title>Comparison of Virtual Machines for Mac OS X; VMware, VirtualBox, Parallels, Q</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/comparison-virtual-machines-mac-os-x-vmware-virtualbox-parallels-q/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/comparison-virtual-machines-mac-os-x-vmware-virtualbox-parallels-q/</guid><description>This article describes briefly what Virtual Machines are, why they are useful, and compares some VM software for Mac OS X:
As web developers, it is often our responsibility to ensure that the websites we build are accessible by users of any common web browser and operating system. Since some browsers are only available on a limited selection of OSes, or behave differently on different OSes, it is impossible to be able to test a website on all browsers with one operating system; In order to test websites frequently, we need to have ready access to a variety of operating systems.</description></item><item><title>Config To Code Module Is Like Features For Drupal 5</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/config-code-module-features-drupal-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/config-code-module-features-drupal-5/</guid><description>Config to Code module for Drupal 5 makes it easy to deploy new views and panels and to version-control changes to existing ones with a source code repository like subversion. It makes it quick and easy to move configured views and panels in the database to code, then safely delete the configured views from the database and finally, expose the views and panels in code back to their respective modules.</description></item><item><title>Congratulations Marco (GHOP student)</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/congratulations-marco-ghop-student/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/congratulations-marco-ghop-student/</guid><description>I just completed a pass on all of the usability issues created by Marco.RobotAngel for GHOP task #48 and I wanted to say well done Marco! :)
The task was to take all of the excellent feedback and suggested solutions in Factory Joe's review and task-ify them or create patches if the solution was simple. This sounds like an easy task, but is in fact very difficult considering the amount of excellent usability feedback Factory Joe gave us.</description></item><item><title>Conservation Strategy Fund Uses Drupal</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/conservation-strategy-fund-uses-drupal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/conservation-strategy-fund-uses-drupal/</guid><description>Conservation Strategy Fund (CSF) recently launched their new Drupal website and the HydroCalculator Tool, both by CivicActions.&amp;nbsp; CSF's mission is to teach environmental organizations around the world to use economics and strategic analysis to conserve nature.&amp;nbsp; Their new website empowers them to do this with multi-lingual features, news streams and feeds, listings that can be filtered by continent, region, country or theme, tight integration with Salesforce.com for donations and newsletter subscribers and a range of detail about the training courses on offer, projects, and publications.</description></item><item><title>Contextual Help in Module Development</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/contextual-help-module-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/contextual-help-module-development/</guid><description>One of the findings of the Drupal usability testing at UMN in February was that users like, use and like to use contextual help. Many of the participants explicitly said that they would have liked more of it during their evaluations and in debriefing.
As a developer it is difficult to anticipate where contextual help is appropriate, needed or perhaps why it's even necessary. While usability testing is possibly the only way to effectively determine exactly where contextual help is needed and useful and where it's not, I think this example might help developers understand when where and why contextual help is likely to be helpful.</description></item><item><title>Customizing "View More" Links In Views 1 For Drupal 5</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/customizing-view-more-links-views-1-drupal-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/customizing-view-more-links-views-1-drupal-5/</guid><description>A short, quick and easy tip for views theming and customization.
To customize the text or the destination path/url of a 'view more' link in Views. Add this to template.php in your phptemplate theme and add cases.
&amp;lt;?php/** * Override theme_views_more() to set custom link texts and destinations. * @param $path String *&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The destination of the more link. */function _phptemplate_views_more($path) {&amp;nbsp; $text = 'more';&amp;nbsp; switch ($path) {&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; case 'foo/bar':&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; $text = 'doh';&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; break;&amp;nbsp; }&amp;nbsp; return "</description></item><item><title>Design Coding</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/design-coding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/design-coding/</guid><description>Classic!</description></item><item><title>Designing the Web for today's devices</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/designing-web-todays-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/designing-web-todays-devices/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Development time to code relationships</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/development-time-code-relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/development-time-code-relationships/</guid><description> My favourite! :)
The first 90% of the code accounts for the first 90% of the development time. The remaining 10% of the code accounts for the other 90% of the development time.</description></item><item><title>Do General Public GET Open Source?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/do-general-public-get-open-source/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/do-general-public-get-open-source/</guid><description>This article about SilverStripe "giving away their product" completely misses the point of open source. I think that like most of the general public here in NZ (perhaps worldwide?), the author understands that "open source is free" (like free beer), but misses the point that SilverStripe's software, and open source in general, is not free because it costs nothing, but because the code that is written to create the software, is open for anyone to use, look at, modify, enhance, learn from, redistribute, sell, print out and use as toilet paper, or glorify in a nice picture frame above their mantlepiece.</description></item><item><title>Do It Right The First Time; Do Not Use Microsoft-Contrived Version Targeting</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/do-it-right-first-time-do-not-use-microsoft-contrived-version-targeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/do-it-right-first-time-do-not-use-microsoft-contrived-version-targeting/</guid><description>Microsoft announced in January that Internet Explorer 8 (IE8) would be standards-compliant, but only if you included a special meta tag or http header indicating that the page should be rendered in standards compliance mode. The uproar from the standards community led Microsoft to change the default behavior of IE8. Now IE8 will render all pages in standards mode by default, unless you specify otherwise with the X-UA-Compatible meta tag or http header.</description></item><item><title>Does Open Source Have Commercial Viability</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/does-open-source-have-commercial-viability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/does-open-source-have-commercial-viability/</guid><description>"Does Open Source Have Commercial Viability?" is a response to my review of Xero.com by Stuart Bale, Product Manager at MYOB. Today he left a comment to let me know about it.
This isn't my reply -- I don't think I can be bothered. But I know there are a lot of people that disagree and care enough to reply.</description></item><item><title>Douglas to give me £8.5m GBP?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/douglas-give-me-%c2%a385m-gbp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/douglas-give-me-%c2%a385m-gbp/</guid><description>UPDATE: Can anyone tell me why this page gets so many hits?
Good ol' 'Douglas Smith' of Prime Bank (at least the bank is real) wants to give me half of the £8.5 million pound sterling he's trying to steal from the bank:
I am an auditor for PRIME BANK London, during my last auditing I realized an unclaimed Bank Draft of 8,528,000GBP
(Eight Million Five Hundred and Twenty Eight Thousand GBP).</description></item><item><title>Dries Buytaert in Brisbane for DrupalDownunder</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/dries-buytaert-brisbane-drupaldownunder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/dries-buytaert-brisbane-drupaldownunder/</guid><description>DrupalDownunder is just 2 months away and is expected to be a sell-out event, with Dries Buytaert (the Drupal project lead and founder) presenting a keynote and attending.
The keynote speakers are:
Dries Buytaert, Drupal project founder and lead New Zealand's own Josh Waihi Josh Koenig Allie Micka DrupalDownunder is on Saturday 22 and Sunday 23 January 2011. Registrations are now open at drupaldownunder.org/registration. The earlybird price is $132 AUD.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 6 Book Review: Building Powerful And Robust Websites With Drupal 6</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-book-review-building-powerful-and-robust-websites-drupal-6-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-book-review-building-powerful-and-robust-websites-drupal-6-0/</guid><description>Perhaps I am too critical or my expectations are too high. In any case I was disappointed with Building Powerful and Robust Websites with Drupal 6. It may be somewhat useful for Drupal beginners seeking an introduction, general guidance or even basic help, but it lacks the detail and usefulness beginners are likely to need to get tasks done early on. I would expect most Drupal beginners to require more complete and comprehensive resources than what this book provides.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 6 Book Review: Building Powerful And Robust Websites With Drupal 6</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-book-review-building-powerful-and-robust-websites-drupal-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-book-review-building-powerful-and-robust-websites-drupal-6/</guid><description>Perhaps I am too critical or my expectations are too high. In any case I was disappointed with Building Powerful and Robust Websites with Drupal 6. It may be somewhat useful for Drupal beginners seeking an introduction, general guidance or even basic help, but it lacks the detail and usefulness beginners are likely to need to get tasks done early on. I would expect most Drupal beginners to require more complete and comprehensive resources than what this book provides.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 6 Themes Book Review</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-themes-book-review-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-themes-book-review-0/</guid><description>Drupal 6 Themes by Ric Shreeves on Packt Publishing is a great resource for newbie Drupal themers. Themers who are not from a programming background will find it especially useful since it starts with the basics and builds up to more complex yet powerful techniques such as hook_form_alter().
read more</description></item><item><title>Drupal 6 Themes Book Review</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-themes-book-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-6-themes-book-review/</guid><description>Drupal 6 Themes by Ric Shreeves on Packt Publishing is a great resource for newbie Drupal themers. Themers who are not from a programming background will find it especially useful since it starts with the basics and builds up to more complex yet powerful techniques such as hook_form_alter().
read more</description></item><item><title>Drupal at Linux Conference Australasia, Wellington January 2010</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-linux-conference-australasia-wellington-january-2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-linux-conference-australasia-wellington-january-2010/</guid><description>Linux Conference Australasia (aka LCA, linux.conf.au) will be in Wellington 18-23 January 2010 – 6 and a half months from now. This presents opportunities for the NZ Drupal community to; Promote Drupal in the wider FLOSS community (which is good for business) Run a DrupalCamp/Conference; which allows attendees to combine expenses if attending LCA, and organizers to share venue, admin, financial and other resources with LCA. Just hang out and drink &amp;amp; talk Drupal!</description></item><item><title>Drupal Downunder 2012 is 2 months away, Session proposals close Monday</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-downunder-2012-2-months-away-session-proposals-close-monday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-downunder-2012-2-months-away-session-proposals-close-monday/</guid><description>Drupal Downunder 2012 is just 2 months away and session proposals close this Monday!
The second Drupal Downunder will be Australasia's biggest Drupal event ever, with Dries Buytaert returning for his second DrupalDownunder, and other keynotes from Dimitri Gaskin and Gian Wild.
And tonnes of other great content, tutorials and sessions by other Drupalistas from Australia, New Zealand and beyond.
If you have been thinking about submitting a session proposal about that really interesting project, client or code you worked on recently, or have some special skill set you want to share with the Drupal community, get your ideas into words this weekend and submit a session proposal by this Monday 14 November to have it considered for the programme.</description></item><item><title>Drupal Gotchya: Cache_get() Returns Expired Items</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-gotchya-cacheget-returns-expired-items/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-gotchya-cacheget-returns-expired-items/</guid><description>cache_get() returns $cache objects even if the cached item is stale (expired). The cached data will not be rebuilt every hour in the following example:
&amp;lt;?php
/**
* Builds complicated data for the monkey grip.
*/
function custom_monkey_grip_data() {
&amp;nbsp; // Return the cached data
&amp;nbsp; $cache = cache_get('custom:monkey_grip');
&amp;nbsp; if (!$cache) {
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; // Some expensive processing to build the data.
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; $data = complicated_recursion_and_loops_on_lots_of_data();
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; // Cache the data and rebuild it every hour</description></item><item><title>Drupal meetup in Auckland New Zealand this Friday</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-meetup-auckland-new-zealand-friday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-meetup-auckland-new-zealand-friday/</guid><description>I'm going to be in Auckland this Friday and am meeting up with some other Drupalers to drink, dine and talk Drupal. Please see my post on groups.drupal.org for more details and to let us know if you're coming.</description></item><item><title>Drupal NZ</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-nz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-nz/</guid><description>Drupal NZ is launched at Drupal.net.nz.
It needs content and people to configure the modules etc...
Go sign up!</description></item><item><title>Drupal Success; What Would Drupal Do?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-success-what-would-drupal-do/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupal-success-what-would-drupal-do/</guid><description>Now that I have been a full-time Drupal Developer for a couple of years, and a part-time Drupal developer for a year before that, I am beginning to recognize recurring patterns and problems in Drupal projects and people's experiences with Drupal. This is a report on my experiences, and a summary of learned lessons and recommendations for those entertaining the idea of a financially-driven Drupal project. Executive Summary Don't undertake a Drupal project without, at the very least, someone on the team or available to the team, to check solutions are architected the Drupal way, monitor development for employment of good practices, look for learning opportunities for the less-experienced Drupal developers on the team, and be available in a timely manner to answer the question What would Drupal do?</description></item><item><title>Drupal+Melbourne: Lullabots, Mini-drupal-conference, DrupalCon? and more...</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalmelbourne-lullabots-mini-drupal-conference-drupalcon-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalmelbourne-lullabots-mini-drupal-conference-drupalcon-and-more/</guid><description>I just heard on the lullabot podcast #53 that lullabot is going to Melbourne to run training sessions in April 2008.
With the Drupal Mini Conf after Linux Conference Australia, and Lonely Planet launching their drupal development in Melbourne, it seems like Melbourne is shaping up to be the “Drupal Capital” of the Southern hemisphere.
Good place for a future DrupalCon?</description></item><item><title>DrupalCon Asia-Pacific Organizers Invite You to Participate</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-asia-pacific-organizers-invite-you-participate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-asia-pacific-organizers-invite-you-participate/</guid><description>We are excited to announce the DrupalCon Asia-Pacific Organisers group. DCAPO intends to lay foundations that will facilitate international Drupal Conferences (DrupalCons) in the Asia-Pacific region.
DCAPO welcomes and needs input and assistance from Drupal users and communities throughout the Asia-Pacific region. DrupalCons are a lot of work, and are only possible through the community's effort. Please join the DCAPO group to share your opinions and experience, volunteer your time, or nominate yourself or others for roles on the selection team.</description></item><item><title>DrupalCon Boston 2008 Confirmed?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-boston-2008-confirmed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-boston-2008-confirmed/</guid><description>UPDATE: DrupalCon Boston 2008 has now been officially announced.
Judging by boston2008.drupalcon.org it seems that the planning of DrupalCon Boston March 2008 is well underway. I've even seen emails with dates about session-planning, yet I can't find any news or announcements about it anywhere. What's going on? Is Boston 2008 confirmed? How come there have been no announcements?
I have been wondering for a while now when there would be some news about the next DrupalCon.</description></item><item><title>DrupalCon Session: Scalable Theming: Theming for 100s of node types, CCK fields, and views</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-session-scalable-theming-theming-100s-node-types-cck-fields-and-views/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-session-scalable-theming-theming-100s-node-types-cck-fields-and-views/</guid><description>One of my 3 DrupalCon Session Proposals got accepted and was scheduled last week: Scalable Theming: Theming for 100s of node types, CCK fields, and views.
Advanced theming tips, tricks and techniques for very large complex websites with many node types, CCK fields and views. This session is targeted at themers &amp;amp; developers wishing to learn how to manage complex theming requirements in a cost-saving, maintainable and scalable way.</description></item><item><title>DrupalCon: jQuery for Designers &amp;amp; Themers</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-jquery-designers-themers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalcon-jquery-designers-themers/</guid><description>jQuery for Designers and Themers is a fun interactive session on getting started with jQuery. It is targeted at designers and themers but is suitable for anyone with a decent understanding of HTML and CSS — no programming experience is necessary. It doesn't include any PHP, and only basic programming concepts are introduced.
If you want to see this session at DrupalCon San Francisco you'll need to vote on it here it is at 8:30am on Tuesday 20 April in room 307 (Commerce guys) at DrupalCon SF.</description></item><item><title>Drupalgeddon; Are you ready?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalgeddon-are-you-ready/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalgeddon-are-you-ready/</guid><description>Just arrived here? Read my followup first.
Original post The Drupal security team announced multiple highly critical updates to Drupal contrib modules in PSA-2016-001. Expect attacks within less than one hour from the announcement; 18 hours from the time this article is published. This is probably going to be Drupalgeddon all over again.
My advice If you are prepared, you will save yourself a lot of time. If you are late or too slow, you will probably find yourself with a lot more work, e.</description></item><item><title>Drupalsites.net</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsitesnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsitesnet/</guid><description>There are several efforts around to collect links and summaries of drupal sites. This is by far the most comprehensive I've seen so far. Sites are categorized by region and other useful terms; http://www.drupalsites.net/</description></item><item><title>DrupalSouth returns!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-returns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-returns/</guid><description>Four years after the last DrupalSouth, and three fantastic Australasian Drupal conferences later, DrupalSouth returns!
DrupalSouth Wellington 14-16 February 2014 is setting up to be a great event! With an awesome venue, large capacity and amazing sponsors, things are well on track.
I co-organised the previous two DrupalSouth's in Christchurch 2008 and Wellington 2010. Josh Waihi is leading the charge for this great event. I am chair for the front end track.</description></item><item><title>DrupalSouth Wellington A Success</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-wellington-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-wellington-success/</guid><description>DrupalSouth Wellington 2010 was a booming success! And that would be an understatement. 100 Drupallers from NZ, Australia, North America and Europe came together for 2 Wellington-wet days in a brewery and couldn't stop talking about Drupal!
Here is DrupalSouth by the numbers;
1: Code sprints 2: Tracks (simultaneous sessions) 2: Duration in days 2: Lunches provided 2: Organisers 2: Attendees from parliament (Green party) 3: Keynote speakers from North America (Liz Henry, Emma Jane Hogbin &amp;amp; Angela Byron) 3: Platinum Sponsors 3: DrupliBeanBags 4: Attendees from the IRD 5: Gold sponsors 5: Percent of attendees from Hawkes bay 5: Months to organise 6: Companies involved in the wireless internet 6: Wireless access points 7: Value of each bar token in NZ dollars 8: Silver Sponsors 9: Varieties of beer brewed on-site 10: Start time on Saturday 11: Thousands of dollars turned over in event production 15: Attendees from NZ government agencies (IRD, Greens, NZ Police, various ministries, etc.</description></item><item><title>DrupalSouth Wellington NZ January 2010</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-wellington-nz-january-2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-wellington-nz-january-2010/</guid><description>Following in the success of DrupalSouth Christchurch November 2008, DrupalSouth Wellington January 2010 is in it's planning stages. It will be close to LCA Wellington 2010 both in time and location, and will feature excellent overseas and home-grown speakers &amp;amp; attendees, such as; Angela Byron (webchick); Drupal 7 core committer, Drupal community nurturer, and co-author of Using Drupal Addison Berry (add1sun); Documentation lead, recipient of $100,000 Knight Foundation grant for Drupal documentation, co-author of Using Drupal Emma Jane Hogbin (emmajane); co-author of Front End Drupal, uber-documenter, Drupal evangelist/speaker and community all-rounder Dan (dman); Numerous drupal modules and high-profile NZ websites including The Vintage Aviator and Sorted.</description></item><item><title>DrupalSouth Write Up</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-write-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-write-0/</guid><description>DrupalSouth was a great success. As New Zealand's first nation-wide Drupal event, many weren't sure what to expect. However it seems that most expectations were exceeded; presentations were useful and interesting, ad-hoc unconference time was valuable, food was on time and tasty, beer was drunk and appreciated and most importantly, a good time was had by all!
There are some great photos on flickr, a long list of tweets on Twitter, and some write-ups by Michael Dance and Brenda "</description></item><item><title>DrupalSouth Write Up</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-write/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/drupalsouth-write/</guid><description>DrupalSouth was a great success. As New Zealand's first nation-wide Drupal event, many weren't sure what to expect.read more</description></item><item><title>Ever need a free version of X?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ever-need-a-free-version-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ever-need-a-free-version-x/</guid><description>A great directory of FLOSS alternatives http://www.webi.org/osalternative.html</description></item><item><title>Favorite text editor in web browser</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/favorite-text-editor-web-browser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/favorite-text-editor-web-browser/</guid><description>I spend a lot of time on the read-write web. I work on a lot of large complicated documents on the web. I often copy text from forms in my web browser to a text editor that is easy to use. I am sick of using basic text editors that web browsers have. This however is a less than ideal workflow.
I would love to have my favorite text editor embedded in my favorite web browser.</description></item><item><title>Feriana.co.nz Drupal 6 Showcase</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ferianaconz-drupal-6-showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ferianaconz-drupal-6-showcase/</guid><description>I recently finished Feriana.co.nz, a simple Drupal 6 site for my fiancée and her handbag business. It uses CCK, Views and Panels 2 alpha, as well as ImageField, ImageCache and Lightbox2 modules. I also wrote Image Themer and Views Themer modules, which I contributed to the Themer package and plan to abstract in to re-usable solutions in my next Drupal 6 theming project which I start this week. I will also be demonstrating these modules at the Advanced Theming Techniques session (if it gets in – Go Vote!</description></item><item><title>Firefox 3 almost stable? And Mac Favicon Theme</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-almost-stable-and-mac-favicon-theme-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-almost-stable-and-mac-favicon-theme-0/</guid><description>I just got this email from Mozilla about the soon release of Firefox 3 release candidate, asking addon developers to get their extensions updated and released for FF3 RCs. If you have an extension released on addons.mozilla.org you would have received this email too. I have two variations of FF2's default Mac theme that enable favicons in the bookmarks toolbar: Mac Favicon and Mac Favicon XL.
read more</description></item><item><title>Firefox 3 almost stable? And Mac Favicon Theme</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-almost-stable-and-mac-favicon-theme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-almost-stable-and-mac-favicon-theme/</guid><description>I just got this email from Mozilla about the soon release of Firefox 3 release candidate, asking addon developers to get their extensions updated and released for FF3 RCs. If you have an extension released on addons.mozilla.org you would have received this email too. I have two variations of FF2's default Mac theme that enable favicons in the bookmarks toolbar: Mac Favicon and Mac Favicon XL. UPDATE: Mac Favicon and Mac Favicon XL have been deprecated and rereleased.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 3 Release Party in Christchurch</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-release-party-christchurch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-release-party-christchurch/</guid><description>Mozilla has finally announced Firefox 3's launch date; this Tuesday 17 June. (Note that's probably US time, so it will be Wednesday in NZ).
Mozilla wants to break a guiness world record for number of downloads in one day and I'm sure they'll achieve it. You can go pledge on spreadfirefox.com (A drupal site): http://www.spreadfirefox.com/en-US/worldrecord
I created a "FF3 launch party" event in Christchurch for kicks on mozillaparty.com: http://mozillaparty.com/en-US/events/view/101</description></item><item><title>Firefox 3, almost converted</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-almost-converted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/firefox-3-almost-converted/</guid><description>I'm almost ready to switch to Firefox 3. There are just a couple of necessary add-ons that I can't live without that I would need to make it my default and main browser;
Undo Closed Tabs Button Mac Favicon XL theme (Since this is my own theme I'll have to update it myself. To get all the benefits of Mac native form widgets and nice new usability improvements I'll base it off FF3's default theme) There are a few other would-be-nice add-ons which I can live without (for a short while at least);</description></item><item><title>Flowtype vs Typescript</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/flowtype-vs-typescript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/flowtype-vs-typescript/</guid><description>Flowtype has a small set of features focussed on typechecking. It is a superset of JavaScript. It can be transpiled to JavaScript by simply stripping the type annotations. It allows you to specify types almost as little or as much you like. It becomes more powerful the more detail you specify. So you can easily leave some or most of your code with no type specifications.
Typescript has a large set of features focussed on classical object oriented concepts like abstract, interface, private and others as well as type checking.</description></item><item><title>For Sale: Apple AirPort Extreme 802.11n Wi-Fi Wireless Base Station - As new</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/for-sale-apple-airport-extreme-80211n-wi-fi-wireless-base-station-as-new/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/for-sale-apple-airport-extreme-80211n-wi-fi-wireless-base-station-as-new/</guid><description>I'm selling my Apple AirPort Base station. This device kicks-arse, but it's now surplus; http://www.trademe.co.nz/Computers/Networking-modems/Wireless-networking...
If you want it for $190 (mates-rates), let me know asap so I can cancel the auction before anyone bids.</description></item><item><title>Gmail Offline Is Here</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/gmail-offline-here/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/gmail-offline-here/</guid><description>Gmail offline is finally here! As per my message on twitter; It's fast – even better than Gmail online. Faster than desktop apps. The internet revolution is here!
You'll need to enable Gmail "Experimental features" first. I've forgotten how to do this, but I think it's in the admin "cpanel" for Google Apps for Your Domain. I'm not sure about Google-proper Gmail.
Once you have that;
go to Settings (in Gmail) then Labs read more</description></item><item><title>Google camera-car detail</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/google-camera-car-detail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/google-camera-car-detail/</guid><description>After yesterday's siting and all the related discussion, the firkin Google car was parked right outside our house today! Well not right outside, but on the other side of the park next to our house -- less than 100 metres away. Celeste called me with the news and I ran out of the house with the camera, socks, no keys, no shoes, front door wide open. A bloke was sitting at a picnic table in the park.</description></item><item><title>Google's Mapping User Experience; Where have you been?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/googles-mapping-user-experience-where-have-you-been/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/googles-mapping-user-experience-where-have-you-been/</guid><description>I've been away from home for the last 12 days. CivicActions' Full-team and Engineering Offsite Advances in Playa Del Carmen, México, started last Tuesday 8 July and finish last Monday 14 July. I arrived in Cancún 6 days early and did some backpacking around the South-East of México, El Petén Northern Guatemala, and Northern Belize.read more</description></item><item><title>Help Get Me to DrupalCon Boston 2008</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/help-get-me-drupalcon-boston-2008/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/help-get-me-drupalcon-boston-2008/</guid><description>I am very involved in drupal usability through the Season of Usability and in the usability group. I will also be attending the formal usability testing of drupal at the University of Minnesota the week before DrupalCon. I have been a mentor for a number of GHOP tasks. I intend to take part in GHOP and UMN panel presentations and also give 1 or 2 presentations individually.
My recent heavy involvement in drupal and the community over the last few months has taken a toll on my income.</description></item><item><title>Help Wanted; QLDfloods.org Drupal 7 Multiple-server Configuration &amp;amp; Infrastructure</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/help-wanted-qldfloodsorg-drupal-7-multiple-server-configuration-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/help-wanted-qldfloodsorg-drupal-7-multiple-server-configuration-infrastructure/</guid><description>There is currently severe flooding in Queensland Australia. An area twice the size of Texas is underwater. Entire homes are completely inundated. Bridges and cars have been washed away like toys. In Brisbane, airports are closed and the CBD has been closed down. There are at least 15 dead and more than 60 still missing.
QLDfloods.org is a Drupal 7 website set up by several members of the Australian Drupal community to provide information, track missing persons, find resources and people that need them (like beds), track damage and provide support.</description></item><item><title>Hook_world_alter() T-shirt Design</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/hookworldalter-t-shirt-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/hookworldalter-t-shirt-design/</guid><description>This hook_world_alter() T-shirt idea was something Trevor Twining came up with way back at DrupalCon DC.&amp;nbsp; I got a single T-shirt made for DrupalCon Paris.&amp;nbsp; A number of people said they wanted one – though since I'm not interested in the business of making T-shirts, I thought I'd make the vector file available for anyone and everyone's use.
Enjoy!
This design is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike license.</description></item><item><title>How Many Different Web Browser Versions Can You Open Simultaneously?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-many-different-web-browser-versions-can-you-open-simultaneously/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-many-different-web-browser-versions-can-you-open-simultaneously/</guid><description>read more</description></item><item><title>How often do you get spammed?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-often-do-you-get-spammed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-often-do-you-get-spammed/</guid><description>I get spammed approximately every 103 seconds. Really. Here are my numbers and calculations; http://spreadsheets.google.com/pub?key=pTpwkDap5YFcnDJ5RRAlIRw
The mailboxes collectively include several catch-all's and many webmaster@ postmaster@ and abuse@ email addresses. I used to publish my email addresses online fairly liberally. Some of the email addresses are several years old and are probably on every single spam-mailing-list.
How many spam emails do you get?
UPDATE: See the follow-up at http://drupal.geek.nz/node/69</description></item><item><title>How to be a climate voter in the NZ general elections</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-be-climate-voter-nz-general-elections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-be-climate-voter-nz-general-elections/</guid><description>In the face of climate change, nothing else is of much significance. NZ 2014 general elections are an opportune time to start reversing humanity's destruction of this planet we call home.
But understanding how to be a "climate voter" can be a challenge. Is it really as simple as voting for the Green party? Lets take a look.
To evaluate which party is most aligned with your own beliefs and priorities, nothing beats reading party policies.</description></item><item><title>How to get the most value out of your programmer</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-get-most-value-out-your-programmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-get-most-value-out-your-programmer/</guid><description>This article about the psychology of programmers hits the nail on the head. Finding it difficult and even impossible to get 'into the flow', was one of the sources of frustration in my recent employment that lead me to resigning.
Now I work virtually for CivicActions and I can create my own space and time to get in the flow and do the fun interesting (and billable) work.
I have experimented working at Effusion's offices, an open-source-centric co-working-like environment in Christchurch over the last 4 weeks.</description></item><item><title>How To Rebuild The Menu In Drupal 6</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-rebuild-menu-drupal-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-rebuild-menu-drupal-6/</guid><description>To rebuild the menu in Drupal 6 you have to go to admin/build/modules.
In drupal 5 the menu is cached in the cache_menu table, so it is easy to invoke a menu-rebuild by emptying the table with a simple mysql command like TRUNCATE cache_menu;. (I have a handy script that empties all tables starting with cache_).
read more</description></item><item><title>How to turn into Free Software supporters people who couldn't care less</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-turn-free-software-supporters-people-who-couldnt-care-less/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-turn-free-software-supporters-people-who-couldnt-care-less/</guid><description>The attachment is a mirror of a great article that is inaccessible and is being slashdotted.</description></item><item><title>How Was DrupalSouth's Internet so Awesome!?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-was-drupalsouths-internet-so-awesome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/how-was-drupalsouths-internet-so-awesome/</guid><description>DrupalSouth — a 100-person technical conference — had awesome internet. This is how we did it.
DrupalSouth might well be the first Drupal conference with internet that didn't suck. For the first time, I didn't hear anyone complain about connectivity or speed. Everyone had internet access! If I didn't hear about any issues you were having, or if you had any complaints or problems, please let us know in the comments.</description></item><item><title>Humour: Flying and Microsoft</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/humour-flying-and-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/humour-flying-and-microsoft/</guid><description>A helicopter was flying around above Seattle when an electrical malfunction disabled all of the aircraft's electronic navigation and communications equipment. Due to the clouds and haze, the pilot could not determine the helicopter's position. The pilot saw a tall building, flew toward it, circled, and held up a handwritten sign that said "WHERE AM I?" in large letters. People in the tall building quickly responded to the aircraft, drew a large sign, and held it in a building window.</description></item><item><title>I am seeking Drupal development contract work</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/i-am-seeking-drupal-development-contract-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/i-am-seeking-drupal-development-contract-work/</guid><description>Contributing to Drupal at DrupalCon Boston March 2008. Photo by Steve Krueger. I am currently available for Drupal development contract work.
I am interested in contracts or projects of any width, height or length. I am especially interested in projects that (roughly in order);
are socially conscious have other talented and experienced Drupal developers to work and grow with compensate at reasonable-to-good rates I am only available to work virtually, since I am based in Thailand (UTC+7) till Christmas, then Wellington, New Zealand (UTC+13) till about late January, then probably Christchurch, NZ after that.</description></item><item><title>I am seeking opportunites</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/i-am-seeking-opportunites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/i-am-seeking-opportunites/</guid><description>I am seeking career opportunities.
My ideal client/employer would;
have a mission related to creating fantastic software or a service. have me work primarily with; Javascript a framework, language or technology that is new to me. value it's team over everything else. contribute to open source. be a not for profit. be making a difference. be in Auckland so I can sit next to my colleagues.</description></item><item><title>I wanna go back to school</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/i-wanna-go-back-school/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/i-wanna-go-back-school/</guid><description>Google will pay high school kids aged 13 to 18 up to $500 for their participation in GHOP. The first round is a bit of a trial and has only ten projects involved, and Drupal is one of them! The others are;
Apache Software Foundation GNOME Joomla! MoinMoin Mono Moodle Plone Python SilverStripe It is both impressive and interesting how many of them are web-content tools (CMS, web-application frameworks, wikis etc).</description></item><item><title>IE6 DeathMarch</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie6-deathmarch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie6-deathmarch/</guid><description>IE6 Death March has led the way in the movement to stop support for IE6. Help your web developers help you to save money, conserve their sanity, build better websites and make the internet a better place. With so many other great browsers available, IE6 is just not worth the effort anymore.
If you think you really need to support IE6, I have two things to say to you;</description></item><item><title>IE6 running on Leopard Mac OS X with IEs4OSX</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie6-running-leopard-mac-os-x-with-ies4osx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie6-running-leopard-mac-os-x-with-ies4osx/</guid><description>Gabor blogged about how IEs4OSX saved drupal.hu. I was impressed with his review so I tried it out myself. Now I don't have to boot up greedy 'ol parallels everyday just to update my hours in Quickbooks (It even runs activeX controls)! :)
I definitely recommend IEs4OSX.</description></item><item><title>IE8 passes Acid2?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie8-passes-acid2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie8-passes-acid2/</guid><description>Dean at M$ reckons IE8 passes the ACID2 face 'test'. I'm dubious. The screen shot is convincing, but I'll believe when I've seen it with my own eyes.
He also rants a bit, trying to pass off web standards as not-so important. His article was also slashdotted.</description></item><item><title>IE8 Version Targetting: ALA, Still Undecided</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie8-version-targetting-ala-still-undecided/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ie8-version-targetting-ala-still-undecided/</guid><description>A List Apart's Issue 253 continues discussing and debating the controversial IE version targeting that ALA announced a month ago. CivicActions blogged about this topic then too.
Jeremy Keith and Jeffrey Zeldman provide very realistic and down-to-earth points of view and arguments both for and against version targeting. Although they each reach different conclusions, neither tries to persuade the reader one way or the other. Rather they leave you more enlightened so that you can make your own decision.</description></item><item><title>Impossible picture on google maps</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/impossible-picture-google-maps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/impossible-picture-google-maps/</guid><description>While psyching myself up for DrupalCon Boston 2008 I was browsing downtown Boston in google maps, I found this weird occurance of an accidental 'impossible picture:
View Larger Map
See this post on my CivicActions blog for more detail: http://www.civicactions.com/blog/impossible_picture_on_google_maps</description></item><item><title>Improving Node Forms With Vertical Tabs</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/improving-node-forms-vertical-tabs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/improving-node-forms-vertical-tabs/</guid><description>Vertical Tabs module by Dmitri Gaskin is a Drupal module-ification of prototype work I did for the usability of Drupal's node forms, and was inspired partly by ideas in the discussion and design process of Views 2 UI – which was all part of my Season of Usability project.
read more</description></item><item><title>Internet Blackout NZ</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/internet-blackout-nz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/internet-blackout-nz/</guid><description>Over the last week Twitter and Facebook users across New Zealand and the world, have been blacking out their avatars in protest of S92A, a change in New Zealand's copyright law that will require ISPs to disconnect any user accused of copyright infringement. No proof or evidence is required, just accusation. This is a terrible law for many reasons, which are well documented on CreativeFreedom.org.nz, and elsewhere.
UPDATE: Internet Blackout NZ is thus far successful.</description></item><item><title>Interview With Bevan Rudge For Lullabot Drupal Voices</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/interview-bevan-rudge-lullabot-drupal-voices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/interview-bevan-rudge-lullabot-drupal-voices/</guid><description> Kent Bye interviewed me (Bevan Rudge) in early September at DrupalCon Paris about Drupal in New Zealand, CivicActions and some recent projects. Yesterday Lullabot released the podcast as Lullabot Drupal Voices 75. Download Audio Import into iTunes or other players Subscribe to feed More options on Lullabot.com It was recorded 2.5 months ago and a couple of things are already out of date. Most significantly; DrupalSouth Wellington 2010 is happening Saturday &amp;amp; Sunday 23-24 January I'm in Thailand and returning to New Zealand on 12 December</description></item><item><title>iPhone Unlocking Service in Christchurch NZ</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/iphone-unlocking-service-christchurch-nz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/iphone-unlocking-service-christchurch-nz/</guid><description>UPDATE: I no longer offer this service.
Original blog post follows... Due to high rank in google search results for queries about unlocked iPhone upgrades to v2 firmware and my recent article about my own experiences. A number of people in Christchurch have contacted me about unlocking their first-generation iPhones that have become locked after upgrading. This is not my trade, and is not something I would consider myself a professional in.</description></item><item><title>Is IPv6 finally here?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/is-ipv6-finally-here/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/is-ipv6-finally-here/</guid><description>"On February 4th, IANA will add AAAA records for the IPv6 addresses of the four root servers." http://it.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/01/03/1954245
Does that mean IPv6 is finally happening? I guess it's time to make sure your web host supports IPv6, or switch to one that does.</description></item><item><title>It's Not "User Testing"</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/its-not-quotuser-testingquot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/its-not-quotuser-testingquot/</guid><description>It's not User Testing!
A number of times recently I have heard folk in the Drupal community and elsewhere talk about User Testing. While many people use this term and it is not strictly incorrect it is misleading and also far from correct A better term to use is Usability testing or UI testing. Here's why;
read more</description></item><item><title>iTerm Upgrade Loses Preferences &amp;amp; Bookmarks</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/iterm-upgrade-loses-preferences-bookmarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/iterm-upgrade-loses-preferences-bookmarks/</guid><description>UPDATE: iTerm version 0.9.5.0821 has been released which is intended to fix this. I haven't tested it.
I just upgraded to iTerm version 0.9.5.0820 from 0.9.5.0611 on Mac OS X Leopard, and found that iTerm had forgotten or lost all of my preferences and bookmarks.
I fixed it by;
quitting iTerm going to ~/Library/Preferences/ moving net.sourceforge.iTerm.plist to net.sourceforge.iTerm.plist~ copying iTerm.plist to net.sourceforge.iTerm.plist starting iTerm See larger image</description></item><item><title>Jakob Neilsen Awards Xero as One of the 10 Best Application UIs of 2008</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jakob-neilsen-awards-xero-one-10-best-application-uis-2008/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jakob-neilsen-awards-xero-one-10-best-application-uis-2008/</guid><description>Jakob Neilsen has written about the 10 best application UIs of 2008. And NZ-made Xero comes in at #10! First of all, congratulations to Xero, the Team and Rod Drury!
Neilsen is recognized as one of the leading usability, analysis and UI design experts in the world. So his recognition of Xero, from little old NZ, is significant. He went one step further and used Xero as an example of how to implement lightboxes / modal dialogues well.</description></item><item><title>jQuery for Designers &amp;amp; Themers at DrupalCon San Francisco</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jquery-designers-themers-drupalcon-san-francisco/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jquery-designers-themers-drupalcon-san-francisco/</guid><description>jQuery for Designers and Themers is a fun interactive session at DrupalCon San francisco on getting started with jQuery. It is targeted at designers and themers but is suitable for anyone with a decent understanding of HTML and CSS — no programming experience is necessary. It doesn't include any PHP, and only basic programming concepts are introduced.
The session is early on Tuesday 20 April in room 307 (Commerce guys) at DrupalCon SF at 8:30am.</description></item><item><title>jQuery.dashboard() in CiviCRM 3.1</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jquerydashboard-civicrm-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jquerydashboard-civicrm-31/</guid><description>In January 2009 I wrote and released jQuery.dashboard() plugin, which extends jQuery to quickly and easily create dashboard UIs like iGoogle. A handful of people have using it for a while, but in December 2009, it was announced that CiviCRM 3.1 would include a dashboard feature utilising jQuery.dashboard() plugin! CiviCRM 3.1 was released late January 2010. (So this blog post is a little late!)
You can try it out yourself at CiviCRM's Drupal demo site.</description></item><item><title>jQuery.dashboard() Plugin</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jquerydashboard-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/jquerydashboard-plugin/</guid><description>The jQuery.dashboard() plugin for jQuery provides a framework that makes it easy for web application developers to create highly configurable dashboard-like user interfaces (similar to iGoogle) in their web applications. Jump straight to the demo.
jQuery.dashboard() requires jQuery UI 1.7's (the new 1.6rc6) Sortable library, which in turn requires jQuery UI Draggable, core and jQuery 1.3.
jQuery.dashboard() requires that a number of serverside callbacks be defined where the current user's widgets per column and minimized status are made available and saved, and where settings for each widget can be retrieved and saved.</description></item><item><title>Last call for DrupalSouth sponsors</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/last-call-drupalsouth-sponsors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/last-call-drupalsouth-sponsors/</guid><description>It is not too late to sponsor DrupalSouth. BUT, there is room for only a few more sponsors and sponsorship closes this Friday 27 November. So if you want to sponsor contact us now!
All sponsors get Logo and link to company profile on sponsors page Detailed company profile on the website Entire team profile on the website Swag in the attendee pack 1 free registration Platinum sponsors get Largest logo on every page on the website Flexible advertising options on the website and at the event Large and prominent printed logo at the venue and on printed materials Acknowledgement in all announcements and media releases Featured article on the website, distributed to all attendees Gold sponsors get Large logo on randomly alternating pages on the website Printed logo at the venue and on printed materials Acknowledgement in some announcements and media releases Silver sponsors get Logo on randomly alternating pages on the website Logo in most printed materials There is room for just 1 more Platinum sponsor from $1000, 2 more Gold sponsors from $500 each and several more Silver sponsors from $200 each.</description></item><item><title>LCD screen comparison; Dell 30" vs MacBook Pro</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/lcd-screen-comparison-dell-30-vs-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/lcd-screen-comparison-dell-30-vs-macbook-pro/</guid><description>While checking out Raincity Studio's drupal work on SpreadFirefox.com I found myself becoming agitated by the bright orange color palette. I whined a little about the design then realized my monitor is partially to blame. The model I have of Dell's 30" LCD monitor (Here's the newer model) has a whopping 1:1000 contrast ratio. Is that what makes firefox-orange so damned bright?
In these photos I've tried (not completely successfully) to capture the difference between the Dell monitor and th MacBook Pro monitor:</description></item><item><title>Learning &amp;amp; Teaching Code Style &amp;amp; Appreciation</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/learning-teaching-code-style-appreciation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/learning-teaching-code-style-appreciation/</guid><description>Yesterday in an informal COSC208 (C and C++ programming) lecture at the University of Canterbury, discussion broke out on how to teach and learn coding Style. Here are my 2 cents;
I believe it's not possible to effectively teach &amp;amp; learn Style with single-developer programs that have a clearly limited life span -- such as all code written for COSC208 and most undergraduate university papers. Once the paper has finished and the grade has been determined, who is going to maintain the student's code?</description></item><item><title>Leopard isn't the new Vista (Firehose on PCmag)</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/leopard-isnt-new-vista-firehose-pcmag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/leopard-isnt-new-vista-firehose-pcmag/</guid><description>Oliver Rist 'reviewed' Mac OS X Leopard and his article was slashdotted.
Disclaimer I'm writing this on my second MacBook Pro, in our house we also have MacBook white (My fiancee's), an iPod Shuffle, an Airport Extreme base station and an Airport Express with Airtunes. Although I wouldn't agree with you, it wouldn't surprise me if you took me for a JAFAF (Just Another Fucking Apple Fanboy). However I make an effort to keep a realistic view on Apple's products and if I felt that an open source operating system could enhance my workflow as much (or nearly as much) as Mac OS X, I would switch, but currently there isn't.</description></item><item><title>Light Fantastic; Backporting A Great Drupal 6 Contrib Theme To Drupal 5</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/light-fantastic-backporting-great-drupal-6-contrib-theme-drupal-5-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/light-fantastic-backporting-great-drupal-6-contrib-theme-drupal-5-0/</guid><description>UPDATE: Buddhika Amila Sampath created the Light Fantastic theme, not Joshua Brauer. Joshua is the maintainer.
I recently searched on Themebot for a great contributed Drupal flexible-width theme for DrupalSouth.net.nz and found Light Fantastic. Joshua Brauer maintains the awesome Light Fantastic theme, which was created by Buddhika Amila Sampath as part of the Google Summer of Code 2007.
Screenshot of Light Fantastic on the DrupalSouth website:
See a larger image.</description></item><item><title>Light Fantastic; Backporting A Great Drupal 6 Contrib Theme To Drupal 5</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/light-fantastic-backporting-great-drupal-6-contrib-theme-drupal-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/light-fantastic-backporting-great-drupal-6-contrib-theme-drupal-5/</guid><description>I recently searched on Themebot for a great contributed Drupal flexible-width theme for DrupalSouth.net.nz and found Light Fantastic. Joshua Brauer created the awesome Light Fantastic theme as part of the Google Summer of Code 2007.
Screenshot of Light Fantastic on DrupalSouth.net.nz:
See a larger image.
read more</description></item><item><title>Listing of all Drupal modules, by KentBye</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/listing-all-drupal-modules-kentbye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/listing-all-drupal-modules-kentbye/</guid><description>This is an interesting and probably also useful view of all contrib modules; http://www.kentbye.com/files/drupal_modules_all.html
and images on Flickr.
KentBye is the creator of the visualise backtrace module, which also kicks arse! Go Kent!</description></item><item><title>Location Package In Drupal 6</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/location-package-drupal-6-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/location-package-drupal-6-0/</guid><description>CivicActions recently undertook a project to review, upgrade, test and patch many contributed Drupal 6 modules to ensure their compatibility with localization (multi-lingual website support). While the endeavour has been supported by Sony BMG for their Drupal multisite on which they run about 80 artist websites and MyPlay.com, the resulting localization-compatible modules will benefit countless Drupal sites including those of some of our other clients when they upgrade to Drupal 6.</description></item><item><title>Location Package In Drupal 6</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/location-package-drupal-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/location-package-drupal-6/</guid><description>CivicActions recently undertook a project to review, upgrade, test and patch many contributed Drupal 6 modules to ensure their compatibility with localization (multi-lingual website support). While the endeavour has been supported by Sony BMG for their Drupal multisite on which they run about 80 artist websites and MyPlay.com, the resulting localization-compatible modules will benefit countless Drupal sites including those of some of our other clients when they upgrade to Drupal 6.</description></item><item><title>Logo Contest Favourites</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/logo-contest-favourites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/logo-contest-favourites/</guid><description>[Update: This had the wrong tag to get on Planet Drupal]
As others have noted, the DrupalCon Boston logo contest is closing soon, so you'd better get your votes in.
Here are my personal favourites;
About 3rd as far as user-votes go, with 36 points; DB8
LauraS only just submitted this one, so it's only got a few votes so far: BoSox style by Don Hajicek at pingVision</description></item><item><title>Lullabot's 50 tips and tricks</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/lullabots-50-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/lullabots-50-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>This is useful even for the most seasoned Drupal user and developer; http://www.lullabot.com/audiocast/podcast-50-drupal-tips-and-tricks</description></item><item><title>Mac Favicon 3</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/mac-favicon-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/mac-favicon-3/</guid><description>UPDATE: Mac Favicon and Mac Favicon XL have been deprecated and rereleased. See http://drupal.geek.nz/blog/mac-favicon-deprecated-and-released
With Firefox 3's release now imminent, a number of people have contacted me about whether there will be a version of my Mac Favicon theme for FF3.
While the short answer is "yes", the long answer is more complicated; I won't be able to take this on anytime soon -- probably not till August. A couple of folk have contacted me about doing it themselves.</description></item><item><title>Mac Favicon Deprecated -- And RELEASED!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/mac-favicon-deprecated-and-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/mac-favicon-deprecated-and-released/</guid><description>Firefox 3 Upgrade? Mac Favicon and Mac Favicon XL themes will not be updated for Firefox 3. However, you can restore this feature in Firefox 3 using userstyles.org and the 'Stylish' Fiefox extension. Click your preferred style below, then click 'Load into Stylish' and follow the instructions from userstyles.org;
Mac Favicon, Firefox 3: show favicons next to bookmark names/titles Mac Favicon XL, Firefox 3: show favicons only (hide bookmark names/titles).</description></item><item><title>MacBook Air notes</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/macbook-air-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/macbook-air-notes/</guid><description>Now I've had almost a day to recover from my yearly applegism, I thought I'd note a few highlighted thoughts on this hot new gadget. Check out my tweets starting from Wednesday 16 January NZST for a full log of my applegasmic experience.
The Ad is beautiful. I seriously admire apple's marketing team.
See the Ad
Steve jobs pulled it out of an envelope at the keynote too. Very cool!</description></item><item><title>Make it work, make it right, make it fast</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/make-it-work-make-it-right-make-it-fast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/make-it-work-make-it-right-make-it-fast/</guid><description>I’ve recently come to appreciate
Make it work, make it right, make it fast.
—&amp;nbsp;Kent Beck Applied to an individual development task, it means to distinctly separate each of these phases of development and to only transition from to the next task when the previous one is complete;
Get the feature to work as fast as possible. The goal here is only to understand the problem and find solution(s).</description></item><item><title>Mapping Raw Text</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/mapping-raw-text/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/mapping-raw-text/</guid><description>This was really interesting; http://www.developmentseed.org/blog/2007/nov/29/we-will-geocode-anything</description></item><item><title>Merry Drupalmas and hAPI New Year!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/merry-drupalmas-and-hapi-new-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/merry-drupalmas-and-hapi-new-year/</guid><description>Christmas wasn't very merry for me; I spent all day in bed and in the bathroom with a wicked tommy-ache and couldn't eat anything. Now it looks like I won't be able to speak at my friends New Year's Eve doo unless my throat improves vastly in the next few hours (At least I can still attend for the mushy food and the atmosphere!). So my NYE probably won't be too happy (though not sad) either.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Tries To Defend NZ Government Contract Failure</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/microsoft-tries-defend-nz-government-contract-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/microsoft-tries-defend-nz-government-contract-failure/</guid><description>Kathryn Ryan of Radio NZ interviewed Don Christie, president of the NZ Open Source Society and Kevin Ackhurst, managing director of Microsoft NZ on Microsoft's failure to renew their multi-million dollar contract with the NZ government.&amp;nbsp; The interviews and Kathryn's questions are intense and very interesting as Don Christie defends the government's choice to break out of a reliance on Microsoft's products, and Kevin Ackhurst tries to defend Microsoft's position, touting it as a success.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft trying to be cool -- using (exploiting?) students as a marketing device</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/microsoft-trying-be-cool-using-exploiting-students-a-marketing-device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/microsoft-trying-be-cool-using-exploiting-students-a-marketing-device/</guid><description>---------- Forwarded message ----------
Date: Mar 17, 2008 9:49 AM
Subject: Microsoft Student Partners 2008
To: all@cosc.canterbury.ac.nz
Hey everyone,
My name is Janina Voigt and I am one of the three Microsoft Student
Partners for 2008. The other Student Partners are Yugan Yugaraja and
Mayur Sampat.
Our role is to bridge the gap between students and academics at
Canterbury, and Microsoft.
We will be carrying out presentations and/or workshops throughout the</description></item><item><title>Migrating to Firefox 3, still not quite ready</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/migrating-firefox-3-still-not-quite-ready/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/migrating-firefox-3-still-not-quite-ready/</guid><description>I got Navigator 9's official EOL notice last week. But FF3 still isn't quite ready for me. Navigator 9 Migrator tool / extension is absolutely useless.
UPDATE: I'm now on FF3 full time and loving it. I'm still missing a couple of features though:
I still need some extensions to migrate fully:
* Undo Closed Tabs
* Firebug
and really really want (almost need):
* Mac Favicon XL (theme)</description></item><item><title>My first Drupal Module -- proposal</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/my-first-drupal-module-proposal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/my-first-drupal-module-proposal/</guid><description>I propose an in-context web-editing interface, and drupal module, that;
is intuitive, allows in-context editing by integrating elements of node-edit form into the view of a node, is minimalistic in it's interface elements, has a working javascript-less interface, has a moderately enhanced interface when js is available (autosave), eliminates the need to use node-edit form for most node-editing and many node-adding use cases, makes the web writable for 'John' that is only used to desktop editing.</description></item><item><title>New roles at NowPublic and the Drupal Association</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/new-roles-nowpublic-and-drupal-association/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/new-roles-nowpublic-and-drupal-association/</guid><description>The new year (this post is a little late!) has brought me new opportunities and some new roles;
As of 21 December 2009, I am a front end Drupal software engineer at NowPublic Technologies Inc, aka NowPublic.com (Clarity Digital Group and Examiner.com). As of 3 March 2010, I am a permanent member on the staff of the Drupal Association.
New job at NowPublic At NowPublic I work on front end theming and customizations for NowPublic.</description></item><item><title>New Zealand Government Rejects Microsoft</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/new-zealand-government-rejects-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/new-zealand-government-rejects-microsoft/</guid><description>The NZ SSC has rejected Microsoft's offers for a new licensing contract. This is a big loss for Microsoft (Though I'm sure MS would have you believe otherwise and try to paint the picture back to front) and big win for NZ Government and NZ's IT industry.
read more</description></item><item><title>Newbie tasks</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/newbie-tasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/newbie-tasks/</guid><description>While reviewing Marco's GHOP issues I found a lot of great issues for Newbie;
http://drupal.org/node/202326
http://drupal.org/node/202343
http://drupal.org/node/202533
http://drupal.org/node/202548
http://drupal.org/node/202538
http://drupal.org/node/201490
http://drupal.org/node/202199
http://drupal.org/node/201565
http://drupal.org/node/202183
http://drupal.org/node/201566
http://drupal.org/node/197460
I couldn't tag them for Newbie, which is why I've posted them here. Is there a way to tag an issue for newbie if you don't own the node?</description></item><item><title>Node Teaser (somewhat) fixed in drupal 6!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/node-teaser-somewhat-fixed-drupal-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/node-teaser-somewhat-fixed-drupal-6/</guid><description>My largest code contribution to Drupal core just got committed! :) At last node_teaser() can take a rest -- at least for a while anyway. It looks like there'll be another round of work on it for Drupal 7).
This was partially sponsored by CivicActions and was a result of work on JustCauseIt.com. Massive kudos to Giles for his extensive testing on this.</description></item><item><title>Not so highly critical?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/not-so-highly-critical/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/not-so-highly-critical/</guid><description>The Drupal security team published a PSA to warn about upcoming security advisories. I shared my advice and predicted attacks within the hour after the security advisories are published. The security advisories are now published. Here is my followup.
I applaud the Drupal Security Team for warning about the highly critical updates. However the public service announcement (PSA) left the impression that this event was going to be much more serious than it was.</description></item><item><title>Nuclear energy policies of NZ political parties</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nuclear-energy-policies-nz-political-parties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nuclear-energy-policies-nz-political-parties/</guid><description>Most kiwis are, unfortunately, too proud of New Zealand's traditional anti-nuclear political stance to keep an open mind on the topic. Media and politics promote the idea that the rest of the world is "impressed" by our political stance. (My impression is that the rest of the world actually thinks our policy is stupid.)
Kiwis are so proud of our nuclear stance, that it would probably be political suicide for a politician or political party to say "</description></item><item><title>NZ Drupal Vendor or Developer needed for Snow and Skateboard Ecommerce Sites</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-drupal-vendor-or-developer-needed-snow-and-skateboard-ecommerce-sites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-drupal-vendor-or-developer-needed-snow-and-skateboard-ecommerce-sites/</guid><description>Online retailers BWMsnow and SKATEgear require the professional services of a Drupal vendor or developer to take over the maintenance and future development their websites.
BWMsnow is NZ's largest online retailer of snowboard gear and has been operating for more than 4 years internationally, focussing more heavily on the NZ market in recent years. BWMsnow was NZ's only online retailer of snowboard gear until recently. BWMsnow is a NZ limited company which continues to grows significantly every selling season (March to June).</description></item><item><title>NZ Government Loves Drupal</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-government-loves-drupal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-government-loves-drupal/</guid><description>The New Zealand Government loves Drupal:
The Beehive's (Parliament building) website runs Drupal Three of the seven represented parties run their websites on Drupal; Labour, Greens and ACT Those three parties represent 57 of the 122 parliamentary seats – almost half! read more</description></item><item><title>NZ is Free of Software Patents!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-free-software-patents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-free-software-patents/</guid><description>We did it! NZ is (very nearly almost) free of software patents!
"We recommend amending clause 15 to include computer programs among inventions that may not be patented. We received many submissions concerning the patentability of computer programs. Under the Patents Act 1953 computer programs can be patented in New Zealand provided they produce a commercially useful effect. Open source, or free, software has grown in popularity since the 1980s.</description></item><item><title>NZ Software Patents; Meeting With Lianne Dalziel, Commerce Committee Chairperson &amp;amp; Labour MP</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-software-patents-meeting-lianne-dalziel-commerce-committee-chairperson-labour-mp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/nz-software-patents-meeting-lianne-dalziel-commerce-committee-chairperson-labour-mp/</guid><description>Today I had a long and very positive meeting about software patents and the NZ Patents Bill with Commerce Committee chairperson, Labour party's Lianne Dalziel, as well as Drupal-peers Dave Lane and Jonathan Hunt.&amp;nbsp; Dalziel, Christchurch East MP, was well-informed about the Patents Bill, the Ministry of Economic Development's Patent Review and the insufficient attention paid to software patents (thanks to our emails and exchange of documents beforehand).&amp;nbsp; She was not so well-informed about software patents and the harm that they cause – as would be expected given the complexity and obscurity of these issues for those who do not work in the software development.</description></item><item><title>Online Protest Successful; Internet Blackout NZ</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/online-protest-successful-internet-blackout-nz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/online-protest-successful-internet-blackout-nz/</guid><description>The online protest against changes to copyright law in New Zealand – aka Internet Blackout NZ – was successful in that it has resulted in a 4-week delay. It is expected that this will give the new New Zealand government enough time to reconsider the consequences of such a ridiculous law change, and most probably repeal the changes entirely. The NZ Herald has more details.
This is an enormous shout out to everyone who drove the protest and participated in some way.</description></item><item><title>OT: Humourous Signs on the West Coast (New Zealand)</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ot-humourous-signs-west-coast-new-zealand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/ot-humourous-signs-west-coast-new-zealand/</guid><description>On a road Trip to the West Coast (New Zealand), we found the merchandise, prices and marketing rather peculiar. This store had a particular broad but limited range of products and services:
While the petrol in Ikamatua seemed just a little over-priced:</description></item><item><title>Pagerank 5 on my blog</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/pagerank-5-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/pagerank-5-my-blog/</guid><description>I just discovered I have page rank 5 on my drupal blog. Wow!</description></item><item><title>Patents? Inventive? WTF?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/patents-inventive-wtf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/patents-inventive-wtf/</guid><description>This is why patents are ridiculous;
On Tuesday, the USPTO granted Microsoft a patent for privacy policy change notification, which describes how to threaten users with the loss of their accounts and access to web sites and services should they refuse to consent to changes in a privacy policy. This includes the case where a user might object to allowing personal information, collected earlier with a promise of confidentiality, to be shared in the future with third parties.</description></item><item><title>Programmers don't create good graphical user interfaces</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/programmers-dont-create-good-graphical-user-interfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/programmers-dont-create-good-graphical-user-interfaces/</guid><description>I think this came from an article on UXmatters:
Databases are one of the ways of organizing information. And it's really popular due to the specifics of computers. Computers work great with numbers. Slicing data into small parts, organizing it, and indexing is what computers do great and fast.
People, though, don't organize information that way in their heads. Associations between objects are too complex and differ from one person to another.</description></item><item><title>Quote: Belt sander in the eye</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/quote-belt-sander-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/quote-belt-sander-eye/</guid><description>This one is from a javascript file by an unknown colleague at CivicActions.
* WARNING * WARNING * WARNING * WARNING
* there is a rediculous amount of stupidity going on here to deal with
* safari + ie + ff + tabs + gmaps + form data
* don't mess with this unless you enjoy a belt sander in the eye.
Judging by the type of humor I think I know who it is.</description></item><item><title>Quote: My native language is Drupal</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/quote-my-native-language-drupal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/quote-my-native-language-drupal/</guid><description>Chx in IRC
my native language is Drupal / PHP
from Chx can not be distracted dot com. lol
See more quotes.</description></item><item><title>Quote: Use a laptop the way it was intended</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/quote-use-a-laptop-way-it-was-intended/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/quote-use-a-laptop-way-it-was-intended/</guid><description> Last night at The Valley In Christchurch:
[Get a MacBook] then you can use a laptop the way it was intended</description></item><item><title>Rainbow Tag Cloud</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/rainbow-tag-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/rainbow-tag-cloud/</guid><description> This tag cloud is great! The implementation isn't ideal with the font tag, but it works nicely and is quite effective from a usability POV too;</description></item><item><title>Recommended article on web usability and eye-tracking</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/recommended-article-web-usability-and-eye-tracking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/recommended-article-web-usability-and-eye-tracking/</guid><description>This great article on web readability and usability based on results of eye-tracking analysis was fairly unsurprising for me, except for this snippet;
Clean, clear faces in images attract more eye fixation. While they might look good with your design, abstract and artsy photos aren’t going to garner much reader attention. If you’re using photos with people in them, make sure they are clear, easy to read shots. It should also be noted that photos with “real” people, not models, perform better.</description></item><item><title>Registrations open for DrupalSouth Wellington, the NZ Drupal event</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/registrations-open-drupalsouth-wellington-nz-drupal-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/registrations-open-drupalsouth-wellington-nz-drupal-event/</guid><description>DrupalSouth registrations opened a couple of days ago and there are already almost 30 registered attendees! Capacity is limited to 100 and it is expected to sell out, so get in quick!
Registration costs just $67.50 NZD including GST ($60 for non-NZ businesses) and includes lunch, coffee and tea on both days – not to mention access to a great line up of speakers and sessions on awesome topics. Here is the full announcement;</description></item><item><title>Reporting a bug on TradeMe -- A Rant</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/reporting-a-bug-trademe-a-rant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/reporting-a-bug-trademe-a-rant/</guid><description>So I found an obscure bug on TradeMe, but there is no way to report it. The contact us section just led to an unhelpful help page. The only email address I could find was mediaenquiries@trademe.co.nz on the Corporate enquiries page. So in order to report the bug I have to blog about it, so I can pass it off as media. Frick! How hard would it be to have a contact form that is read and where useful messages are directed accordingly and other messages are ignored.</description></item><item><title>Review of Drupal Contrib Themes</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/review-drupal-contrib-themes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/review-drupal-contrib-themes/</guid><description>Dan Lennox @ emspace has gone to a lot of trouble reviewing drupal's contrib themes. This is really useful for anyone seeking a contrib theme for their client's site.
It would be great to have this sort of data available on d.o to make it maintainable in the long term. Continue discussion at groups.drupal.org</description></item><item><title>Richard Stallman on Free Software In Christchurch</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/richard-stallman-free-software-christchurch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/richard-stallman-free-software-christchurch/</guid><description>On Saturday I was fortunate to be able to see Richard Stallman speak right here in Christchurch, NZ. He spoke on "free software in ethics and practice"; the issues of non-free software, how it affects our society, what the FSF is doing about it, what we as individuals and computer users can do about it and free software in schools and education. He spoke extensively on the "four freedoms" that software users should be entitled to and even suggested they should be classed as human rights.</description></item><item><title>Sample Code For JQuery For Designers And Themers, DrupalCon Paris 2009</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/sample-code-jquery-designers-and-themers-drupalcon-paris-2009/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/sample-code-jquery-designers-and-themers-drupalcon-paris-2009/</guid><description>I was extremely pleased with my DrupalCon Paris session on jQuery for Designers and Themers. It was a great success – my best session yet.
You can see the slides at tinyurl.com/jQuery-Designers and download the sample theme code from drupal.org/project/jq4dat.
I made a couple of references to blog posts and work I've done with jQuery during the session:
I wrote a jQuery dashboard plugin that uses jQuery UI's Sortable library to make an iGoogle-like dashboard with an example server-side implementation.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Up Usability Testing In Drupal</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/scaling-up-usability-testing-in-drupal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/scaling-up-usability-testing-in-drupal/</guid><description>Still not sure why usability testing is important? See what a linux hobbyist found in an informal usability test on Ubuntu. Usability testing (hereafter "UT") is getting a lot of attention in Drupal -- and rightly so IMHO. If we aim to have "100%" test coverage on Drupal's code and functionality for Drupal 7, it stands to reason we also need test "coverage" on Drupal's usability. If not, it's far too easy for bad interfaces to be developed that pass all the functional and unit tests, but fail miserably in the real world!</description></item><item><title>Scaling Up Usability Testing In Drupal</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/scaling-usability-testing-drupal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/scaling-usability-testing-drupal/</guid><description>Still not sure why usability testing is important? See what a linux hobbyist found in an informal usability test on Ubuntu.
Usability testing (hereafter "UT") is getting a lot of attention in Drupal -- and rightly so IMHO. If we aim to have "100%" test coverage on Drupal's code and functionality for Drupal 7, it stands to reason we also need test "coverage" on Drupal's usability. If not, it's far too easy for bad interfaces to be developed that pass all the functional and unit tests, but fail miserably in the real world!</description></item><item><title>Scheduled Publishing with Workbench Moderation</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/scheduled-publishing-workbench-moderation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/scheduled-publishing-workbench-moderation/</guid><description>Originally posted at PreviousNext.com.au.
Scheduler module allows content editors to specify times for content to be published and/or unpublished. However it is not compatible with Workbench Moderation module, which allows content to have states like “draft” and “needs review” rather than just “published” or not.
Scheduler Workbench is a new module that integrates Workbench Moderation and Scheduler modules, so that content can be configured to become published or unpublished and be assigned a new moderation state at a date and time specified by the content editor.</description></item><item><title>Security vulnerabilities in UserPro plugin for WordPress</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/security-vulnerabilities-userpro-plugin-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/security-vulnerabilities-userpro-plugin-wordpress/</guid><description>UserPro plugin for WordPress versions up to 2.28 have multiple security vulnerabilities that expose the website they are installed on to a wide scope of attack vectors. The plugin has 27 occurrences a procedure call that is extremely insecure (extract($_POST)) and a futher 57 probably insecure uses of extract().
Upon discovering these security vulnerabilies I reported them to Envato, who sells the plugin on behalf of the author on CodeCanyon.</description></item><item><title>Seeking junior PHP developer</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/seeking-junior-php-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/seeking-junior-php-developer/</guid><description>Graduate software engineer at Archetypes.com Work for an innovative internet startup company, breaking new ground in the areas of social networking and self-understanding.
Salary range: $50,000 to $70,000 NZD
Location: Devonport, Auckland
Start: early May
About you You are finishing your studies in software engineering or computer science and are seeking experience. Internet technology excites you. You are thorough. And passionate about finding simple solutions for complicated problems.
You are a great programmer.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Theming Skills At DrupalCon</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/sharpen-your-theming-skills-drupalcon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/sharpen-your-theming-skills-drupalcon/</guid><description>Theming is one of the aspects of Drupal development that Drupalers most want to get better at, according to Dries' last survey.
read more</description></item><item><title>SignOn.org.nz, By Greenpeace NZ</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/signonorgnz-greenpeace-nz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/signonorgnz-greenpeace-nz/</guid><description>Earlier this year Jenn, Owen and I worked on a proposal for Greenpeace NZ. CivicActions didn't win the contract, but the website has just launched.
SignOn.org.nz – a Drupal site – was implemented by Catalyst IT, a FLOSS software shop in Wellington New Zealand which employs Josh "fiasco" Waihi, Drupal 7 PostgreSQL maintainer and NZ IT Rockstar 2009 winner and Brenda "shiny" Wallace, Drupal contributor.
Catalyst has done an excellent job and the campaign was featured in NZ's national Sunday newspaper a couple of weeks ago.</description></item><item><title>Snail Mail Spam From the 'Domain Registry of America'</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/snail-mail-spam-from-domain-registry-america/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/snail-mail-spam-from-domain-registry-america/</guid><description>My first spam by snail mail:
more photos and full letter
What's up with that? Has 'Domain Registry of America' got enough funding to do this seriously? Is anyone else getting spammed from their virtual life by snail mail?</description></item><item><title>Spamusement</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/spamusement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/spamusement/</guid><description> A great collection of cartoons inspired by spam titles. This one's title is; Shake The Extra Fat, You Will Be Surprised</description></item><item><title>Stages of JavaScript grief</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/stages-javascript-grief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/stages-javascript-grief/</guid><description>This is one of my favourite blog posts of all time. It is no longer published, but I found it on the wayback machine (internet archive). I am reposting it here for your enjoyment. I hope the original author doesn't mind.
Originally by By Dan Lee, 9 September 2010.
The typical beginning of an Enterprise Developer’s JavaScript education is involuntary in nature. In many cases an engineer with a strong background in Java, or other strongly-typed languages, is informed that their next project requires JavaScript.</description></item><item><title>Standards Solution to Microsoft's IE8 Version-Targeting Rubbish</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/standards-solution-microsofts-ie8-version-targeting-rubbish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/standards-solution-microsofts-ie8-version-targeting-rubbish/</guid><description>It seems there is a clean standards-solution that doesn't succumb to the X-UA-Compatible mess Microsoft has dumped on us, yet let's you author html in standards mode in IE8:
"John Resig points out something that I think a lot of the mainstream chatter around IE8 has missed - if you send it a currently unused DOCTYPE (like HTML 5,) it will not cower in IE7 mode.
"John examines this feature of IE8 in this post: http://ejohn.</description></item><item><title>Starting at Palantir</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/starting-palantir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/starting-palantir/</guid><description>Today is a new beginning. Today is my first day at Palantir.net. I am now a "Palantiri"! (That's Palantiri-speak for someone who works at Palantir.net. ;)
Palantir.net is a high-end Drupal consulting &amp;amp; services company based in Chicago, Illinois, USA. Palantir.net has a great team of Drupal developers and contributors, including some friends and past colleagues from CivicActions and NowPublic. And I am excited to be a part of that team!</description></item><item><title>Still Wondering What Twitter Is?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/still-wondering-what-twitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/still-wondering-what-twitter/</guid><description>Wonder know more. In 2.5 minutes you'll know:</description></item><item><title>Street View coming to Google maps NZ; Camera-vehicle spotted in Christchurch</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/street-view-coming-google-maps-nz-camera-vehicle-spotted-christchurch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/street-view-coming-google-maps-nz-camera-vehicle-spotted-christchurch/</guid><description>UPDATE: Robert Coup on Web 2.0 showed up my google foo; The NZ Herald published this news just over a week ago.
UPDATE: I met the driver and got detail shots today
UPDATE: The car was spotted in Christhcurch again on 30th of October. Odd.
Today I was crossing Mansfield ave in Merivale, Christchurch when Celeste pointed out a 'Google car'. I looked and saw a small black car pulling off the curb with a Google logo on the side.</description></item><item><title>Synchronized Mail, Contacts, Calendars Across iPhone, Google, Mail.app, iCal.app</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/synchronized-mail-contacts-calendars-across-iphone-google-mailapp-icalapp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/synchronized-mail-contacts-calendars-across-iphone-google-mailapp-icalapp/</guid><description>I have spent considerable time over the last year or so trying to get my data and systems set up to have email, contacts and calendars available both online and offline on both my main computer, my mobile device and online as a guest user on others computers. All the while keeping my inbox clean from spam and bulk mail, contacts synchronized and access my preferred user-interfaces and applications. I've recently been able to get this pretty close to perfect.</description></item><item><title>Tags Vocabularies Without The Pitfalls</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tags-vocabularies-without-pitfalls-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tags-vocabularies-without-pitfalls-0/</guid><description>Drupal's tagging vocabularies are really useful when webmasters and admins can not anticipate what categories or terms content authors and editors are going to need. The pitfall however, is that it is too easy for content editors to make a mess of the vocabulary by creating duplicate terms that are spelled wrong, similar to or synonymous of existing terms. And a "dirty" vocabulary such as this can be rather difficult to clean up and can be a real problem if content needs to be structured.</description></item><item><title>Tags Vocabularies Without The Pitfalls</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tags-vocabularies-without-pitfalls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tags-vocabularies-without-pitfalls/</guid><description>Drupal's tagging vocabularies are really useful when webmasters and admins can not anticipate what categories or terms content authors and editors are going to need. The pitfall however, is that it is too easy for content editors to make a mess of the vocabulary by creating duplicate terms that are spelled wrong, similar to or synonymous of existing terms. And a "dirty" vocabulary such as this can be rather difficult to clean up and can be a real problem if content needs to be structured.</description></item><item><title>Tech Tuesday: Loading GMaps Asynchronously On The Witness Hub</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tech-tuesday-loading-gmaps-asynchronously-witness-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tech-tuesday-loading-gmaps-asynchronously-witness-hub/</guid><description>Last week the Witness Hub was updated with new enhancements and features -- most obviously, the Hub Map is now also on the home page!
Here is a video demonstration:
This feature required asynchronous loading of the Hub Map, including it's full-screen switcher and chunk marker loader code and features, on-load of the 'Map' tab (a Hub-customized version of jQuery tabs).read more</description></item><item><title>Technical Tuesday: IE8 Version Targetting: ALA, Still Undecided</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/technical-tuesday-ie8-version-targetting-ala-still-undecided/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/technical-tuesday-ie8-version-targetting-ala-still-undecided/</guid><description>A List Apart's Issue 253 continues discussing and debating the controversial IE version targeting that ALA announced a month ago. CivicActions blogged about this topic then too.
Jeremy Keith and Jeffrey Zeldman provide very realistic and down-to-earth points of view and arguments both for and against version targeting. Although they each reach different conclusions, neither tries to persuade the reader one way or the other. Rather they leave you more enlightened so that you can make your own decision.</description></item><item><title>Terms of engagement template for freelancers</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/terms-engagement-template-freelancers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/terms-engagement-template-freelancers/</guid><description>Most people who have worked as freelancers for a while will have a story about a client who never paid. Often freelancers just do not have the time to think about getting a lawyer or writing a contract. Indeed the costs of getting a lawyer involved usually outweigh the risks for most freelancer engagements.
However many times, all the freelancer needs is that the client understands how they roll: the terms of how they engage.</description></item><item><title>TextMate &amp;amp; Komodo</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/textmate-komodo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/textmate-komodo/</guid><description>Wow. TextMate still blows me away with its features and bundles. It's the best value software I ever bought. I just discovered some more great features with SVN and CSS bundles on this pretty site:
http://blog.circlesixdesign.com/2006/10/20/textmate-css-editing/ http://blog.circlesixdesign.com/2007/04/18/textmate-svn-bundle/ I've also been using Komodo IDE for debugging for the last week. It's great. A BIG time-saver when you're sure your code is right, but it's still not behaving as you expected.</description></item><item><title>The Writable Web</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/writable-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/writable-web/</guid><description>There are many varying ideas of what "Web 2.0" 'is'. I like the notion that "Web 1.0" is the read-only media-enhanced hyper-linked internet -- where hyperlinks are it's best feature and almost it's foundation -- while "Web 2.0" encompasses the technology that enables media-rich read-write interfaces, on top of everything "Web 1.0" is. While this "Web 2.0" technology is not new, it has been enhanced enabled and made ready for-the-masses.</description></item><item><title>Third Party MacBook Batteries Compared</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/third-party-macbook-batteries-compared/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/third-party-macbook-batteries-compared/</guid><description>I recently needed to purchase two replacement batteries for Apple laptops. One for a MacBook 13-inch white, and one for a MacBook Pro 17-inch. I decided to purchase third-party batteries since the saving was about 30% and they came with a 12-month warranty. While I had the original and third-party replacement batteries in one place, I decided to snap some photos so that others can see the differences between Apple's replacement batteries and third-party ones.</description></item><item><title>This is not a drill: Update Drupal 7 NOW</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/not-drill-update-drupal-7-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/not-drill-update-drupal-7-now/</guid><description>Half of a client's Drupal 7 sites were compromised over the weekend.
If you did not update your Drupal 7 website by about Friday, your site was probably hacked too: Update to Drupal 7.32 or apply the patch manually updating is not trivial.
After that, you will need to review your site's administrator users, permissions, logs and content for unexpected users, roles, permissions, content and and scripts.
Follow or join the conversation in #drupalsa05 for more detail about known exploits and how to repair your hacked site.</description></item><item><title>To Core Developers; I Need You, Please. :)</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/to-core-developers-i-need-you-please/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/to-core-developers-i-need-you-please/</guid><description>I still haven't been able to establish a technical mentor for my SoU project. I need a Drupal developer with a fair amount of Drupal karma and a small interest in usability, for this project to be successful. I'll be plain; I'm directly asking Dries, core developers, and other similarly-respected folk in the Drupal community, for someone who can commit about 3 hours per week for three months. This is a sizable contribution to Drupal and will result in considerable usability improvements.</description></item><item><title>tpl.phps are not templates</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tplphps-are-not-templates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tplphps-are-not-templates/</guid><description>Drupal's template files (*.tpl.php) are not really templates. This is what my DrupalCon core developer summit submission is about. The slides briefly explain why tpl.phps are not real templates, what real templates are, why this is a problem for the Drupal project and community, and mentions some possible solutions to the problem. It also provides some basic guidelines as a starting point for tpl.php standards, should that be pursued.</description></item><item><title>tpl.phps are not templates, Wednesday 11am, room 212, DrupalCon San Francisco</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tplphps-are-not-templates-wednesday-11am-room-212-drupalcon-san-francisco/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/tplphps-are-not-templates-wednesday-11am-room-212-drupalcon-san-francisco/</guid><description>I scheduled the "tpl.phps are not real templates" session and discussion as a BoF session on Wednesday at 11am in room 212 at DrupalCon San Francisco.
From my original post;
"Drupal's template files (*.tpl.php) are not really templates. This is what my DrupalCon core developer summit submission is about. The slides briefly explain why tpl.phps are not real templates, what real templates are, why this is a problem for the Drupal project and community, and mentions some possible solutions to the problem.</description></item><item><title>Translation Links For Semi-Multi-Lingual Drupal 6 Websites</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/translation-links-semi-multi-lingual-drupal-6-websites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/translation-links-semi-multi-lingual-drupal-6-websites/</guid><description>I created the Translation Links module as a way of making translations of nodes easily accessible on partially translated multi-lingual websites. Such websites will have Drupal 6 core's Content Translation module enabled, but not many or perhaps any of i18n and it's modules that enable multi-lingual features for menus, views and taxonomy.
read more</description></item><item><title>UMN Usability photos, Arrival in Boston, It's Snowing! US Culture</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/umn-usability-photos-arrival-boston-its-snowing-us-culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/umn-usability-photos-arrival-boston-its-snowing-us-culture/</guid><description>I arrived in Boston yesterday afternoon, absolutely exhausted after Usability testing at UMN -- which was amazing. See the report at 9am on Monday to hear why. It was snowing heavily here this morning. Today I need to prepare for my presentation on Scalable Theming and my parts of the Usability presentation, and try open another US bank account.
Here's my photoblog to date:
View Album
Get your own</description></item><item><title>UPDATED: Can't Add CSS, JS, RSS Icon Or Set Title Or Messages In Preprocess Page?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/updated-cant-add-css-js-rss-icon-or-set-title-or-messages-preprocess-page/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/updated-cant-add-css-js-rss-icon-or-set-title-or-messages-preprocess-page/</guid><description>UPDATE: Due to recent changes to our website the code snippet (the valuable part of this blog post) got accidentally lost. If you read this already, please come back to see the sample code. Thanks!
Often you want to add CSS files, scripts, feed icons or even set Drupal's page title from the theme layer. The most obvious place to call Drupal's functions for these tasks is probably in a page preprocess function.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade unlocked jail-broken first-generation iPhone to v2 iPhone firmware</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/upgrade-unlocked-jail-broken-first-generation-iphone-v2-iphone-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/upgrade-unlocked-jail-broken-first-generation-iphone-v2-iphone-firmware/</guid><description>My attempt to upgrade my unlocked and jail-broken first-generation iPhone were badly timed with Apple's release of version 2.0.2 firmware about 24 hours beforehand. This meant I initially couldn't use quickpwn because I couldn't restore the 2.0.1 firmware.
Nevertheless quickpwn (windows only) worked once out of 3 attempts on 2.0.2, but wouldn't unlock the phone for my vodafone-NZ prepay SIM card. It stopped everytime after operation 0, and once restarted at operation 5 or so after I disconnected and reconnected the phone.</description></item><item><title>URGENT: Fight for your rights!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/urgent-fight-your-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/urgent-fight-your-rights/</guid><description>NZ government is negotiating a trade act that will impact your civil liberties. And they are doing it behind our backs — in secret!
"ACTA is a controversial international treaty that impacts digital rights and is being negotiated in secret meetings. ACTA is proposed as a plurilateral trade agreement for establishing international standards on intellectual property rights enforcement. It is being negotiated between the US, Canada, Japan, the European Union, South Korea, Mexico, Switzerland, Australia and New Zealand.</description></item><item><title>URGENT: Unlimited Software Patents In New Zealand. Act Now!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/urgent-unlimited-software-patents-new-zealand-act-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/urgent-unlimited-software-patents-new-zealand-act-now/</guid><description>NZ government is about to pass a new Patents Act.&amp;nbsp; In the 8-year review, they seemingly forgot to consider the impacts of patents on computer software!&amp;nbsp; Submissions on the bill are being accepted till 2 July, so we need to move fast.&amp;nbsp; Make a submission now!&amp;nbsp; read more</description></item><item><title>Usability in Drupal 6; 50 golden eggs need some love!</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/usability-drupal-6-50-golden-eggs-need-some-love/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/usability-drupal-6-50-golden-eggs-need-some-love/</guid><description>Chris Messina's (aka Factory Joe) review of drupal 6 is a big contribution to drupal usability. I have highlighted about 50 actionable issues that have been raised and/or discussed through this review. Most of them are trivial changes for drupal 6, but are key usability improvements. Many are simply improving the help text. Some are larger tasks that require more work and changes and should probably wait for drupal 7.</description></item><item><title>Usability Of Car Stereos</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/usability-car-stereos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/usability-car-stereos/</guid><description>For a long time I have wondered how the teams that design car stereos can fail so miserably at making car stereos easy to use. The function of a car stereo is not complicated, and there are few tasks that need to be considered in the design of a car stereo interface. Approximately in order of importance these tasks are;
lower the volume kill the sound raise the volume select the source (e.</description></item><item><title>Usability Testing Suite In Beta, Google Summer of Code</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/usability-testing-suite-beta-google-summer-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/usability-testing-suite-beta-google-summer-code/</guid><description>The Usability Testing Suite is in Beta! Google Summer of Code student Jimmy "boombatower" Berry has been coding hard and fast all this great usability testing tool.
The Usability Testing Suite is intended to be used for remote 'guerilla' usability testing. Currently it allows a usability test designer/engineer to create a study with a bunch of tasks, and invite participants to attempt the task, whilst remotely capturing data about the pages / urls the participant visited, the forms they submitted, what data was entered, and allows the participant to log typed live feedback as they go.</description></item><item><title>Using PHP On Drupal Settings Pages</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/using-php-drupal-settings-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/using-php-drupal-settings-pages/</guid><description>It is generally recognized that CMSes are about separating the content from it's appearance and the logic that manipulates the content. In Drupal, it is good practice to maintain code in files which can be version-controlled (with subversion for example), and keep just the dynamic content and data in the database. In other words, executable code should not go in the database.
read more</description></item><item><title>Version Controlling Drupal Settings Files</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/version-controlling-drupal-settings-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/version-controlling-drupal-settings-files/</guid><description>One of the problems almost every Drupal project or team comes across shortly after adding their Drupal site to a version control system such as Subversion, is whether to version-control the settings.php file or not.
read more</description></item><item><title>Vertical Tabs In Drupal 7 Core! How Open Source Does Usability – The Process</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/vertical-tabs-drupal-7-core-how-open-source-does-usability-%e2%80%93-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/vertical-tabs-drupal-7-core-how-open-source-does-usability-%e2%80%93-process/</guid><description>Vertical tabs are finally in Drupal core!
Screenshot of vertical tabs on an 'Article Edit' page in Drupal 7.
A week ago Angie "webchick" Byron committed a large patch from #323112 Vertical Tabs to Drupal 7 core. This change is quite possibly the most significant usability enhancement to Drupal 7 to date. Two of the three formal usability tests did usability testing with vertical tabs and reported positively.
Screenshot of a 'Story Edit' page in Drupal 6, before vertical tabs.</description></item><item><title>Video of Scalable Theming Session from Drupalcon Boston</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/video-scalable-theming-session-drupalcon-boston/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/video-scalable-theming-session-drupalcon-boston/</guid><description> Drupalcon Boston sessions were all recorded on video and have been made available on archive.org, thanks to numerous drupal community members and other Drupal resources.
(This is quite out of date now, but better late than never.)
Here are the videos from my talk on Scalable Theming: Theming for 100s of node types, CCK fields, and views:
read more</description></item><item><title>Views Filter Blocks In Drupal 6</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/views-filter-blocks-drupal-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/views-filter-blocks-drupal-6/</guid><description>Screenshot of Views 2 exposed filters in a block. This video demonstrates how to setup Views 2 exposed filters as a block.
read more</description></item><item><title>Vote For DrupalCon Sessions</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/vote-drupalcon-sessions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/vote-drupalcon-sessions/</guid><description>Unexpectedly, it appears I will probably be able to attend DrupalCon DC 2009. So I have been working frantically to get my session proposals in. Here they are;
Advanced Theming Techniques; Getting beginner themers up the Drupal theming learning curve. Paper Prototyping To Fix Usability Bugs; Designing and contributing drupal core usability bug fixes. Google Maps Mashups In &amp;lt;10 minutes; Using Drupal's GMap module to create Google Maps mashups on the fly, and showcase of the Hub Map.</description></item><item><title>Vote for Open Source in NZ</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/vote-open-source-nz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/vote-open-source-nz/</guid><description>Are you heading out to vote this morning? Have you thought about how each of the parties support open source? The Greens's IT policy explicitly states a number of policies about encouraging Open Source in Business, Government and Education.
It's hard to beat that! Further; The Greens use Drupal and CiviCRM heavily in both their public-facing and internal systems -- their actions match their words. Go Greens!</description></item><item><title>Web Accessibility Basics</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/web-accessibility-basics-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/web-accessibility-basics-0/</guid><description>CivicActions endeavors that our websites be usable. Usable implies accessible, since a user with special needs can not use an inaccessible site. In this article I discuss techniques that every web developer, themer and front-end html coder should have in their toolkit. These are the low-hanging fruit, the simple and inexpensive techniques, that make a big difference for internet users with restricted access, from user with low bandwidth internet connections, to users with poor eyesight.</description></item><item><title>Web Accessibility Basics</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/web-accessibility-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/web-accessibility-basics/</guid><description>CivicActions endeavors that our websites be usable. Usable implies accessible, since a user with special needs can not use an inaccessible site. In this article I discuss techniques that every web developer, themer and front-end html coder should have in their toolkit. These are the low-hanging fruit, the simple and inexpensive techniques, that make a big difference for internet users with restricted access, from user with low bandwidth internet connections, to users with poor eyesight.</description></item><item><title>Web Apps as Desktop Apps; Prism, Web-Runner &amp;amp; Fluid.app</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/web-apps-desktop-apps-prism-web-runner-fluidapp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/web-apps-desktop-apps-prism-web-runner-fluidapp/</guid><description>With applications moving to the web, the desktop web browser is becoming more and more the center of users' attention. Consider for a moment what percentage of time you spend in Firefox or other web browsers compared to other programs or applications that run in your desktop – or use RescueTime (Yet Another Web App) to find out precisely!
read more</description></item><item><title>What Does A "Themer" do? What Is A "Themer"?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-does-themer-do-what-themer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-does-themer-do-what-themer/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered what a "themer" actually does? How are they different to a designer and a developer? In it's simplest sense a themere takes a flat static image, the design, provided by the designer, and a mostly-functional but ugly site, provided by a developer, and makes the ugly site look pretty like the designer wants it.
This timelapse by Matthew Buchanan of the theming of nzmusicmonth.co.nz sums up that process:read more</description></item><item><title>What happened to my blog?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-happened-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-happened-my-blog/</guid><description>UPDATE Internet Blackout NZ is thus far successful. We successfully delayed changes to Section 92A for 4 weeks! I expect, and we are all hopeful, that this will give the new government time to fully understand their #$@%-up, and dismiss the law change entirely.
The original post follows, and here is what drupal.geek.nz looked like during the week of February 16-23:
Click for full size
It's a blackout! In response to the proposal of the worlds harshest copyright infringement laws, many are protesting with a blackout.</description></item><item><title>What Is Google Hiding With Chrome?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-google-hiding-chrome-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-google-hiding-chrome-0/</guid><description>Google has announced their web browser Chrome. Many are excited while others remain skeptical. Currently I'm both; but a recent discovery has swayed me towards skeptical. Here's why.
read more</description></item><item><title>What Is Google Hiding With Chrome?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-google-hiding-chrome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-google-hiding-chrome/</guid><description>Google has announced their web browser Chrome. Many are excited while others remain skeptical. Currently I'm both; but a recent discovery has swayed me towards skeptical. Here's why.
read more</description></item><item><title>What kind of amazing grace?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-kind-amazing-grace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-kind-amazing-grace/</guid><description>This awesome song by my colleague and friend Ian Rhett moved me. Digg it here.</description></item><item><title>What to do with replies to spam?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-do-with-replies-spam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/what-do-with-replies-spam/</guid><description>Almost a month ago I blogged about how much spam I receive. At that time it was around one spam email per 100 seconds (average over the previous month). Since then I've updated my crude spam rate tracker twice and I'm now receiving approximately one spam every 90 seconds. If you look at the numbers carefully you'll noticed that today's count was less for all mailboxes except one; N L AR, the catch-all address for lucion.</description></item><item><title>Witness Hub</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/witness-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/witness-hub/</guid><description>This video is a graphic summary of what the Hub is;
It has been a real pleasure working with the Witness team at CivicActions on the Hub. I've been working on google maps and geodata integration, all of which boils down to the Hub Map. The next feature I'm currently working on is a full-screen map.
I should have blogged this 8 days ago on international Human Rights day, but I had a good excuse (I was in Australia).</description></item><item><title>Wonderful Webpack tips</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/wonderful-webpack-tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/wonderful-webpack-tips/</guid><description>Here are my recently learnt tips for advanced usage of the wonderful Webpack
--hot does not do would you would expect. webpack --watch and webpack-dev-server do what you'd expect --hot to do, even without that option. --lazy stops WDS from doing what you'd expect --hot to do. --hot allows modules (files) to be updated in place, without reloading the webpage. --open is pretty handy --inline can be moved to webpack.</description></item><item><title>WordPress Company Raises $30 million</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/wordpress-company-raises-30-million/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/wordpress-company-raises-30-million/</guid><description>The late breaking news ripping through the twitter-sphere and hitting the blogosphere is that
Matt Mullenweg, founder of Automattic and creator of open-source blogging system WordPress... raised a whopping $29.5 million in a Series B Round of funding, including a strategic investment from The New York Times Co. True Ventures led the round, which includes previous investors Polaris Ventures and Radar Ventures. (Full disclosure: both Automattic and GigaOM are backed by True Ventures.</description></item><item><title>Writing the Right Stuff, in the 21st Century</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/writing-right-stuff-21st-century/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/writing-right-stuff-21st-century/</guid><description>I was recently discussing the problems of software security and code quality. These articles inspired the conversation;
Everything is Broken, a sincere recount of the awfulness of almost all software. They Write the Right Stuff, how the Shuttle Group makes nearly-perfect software for NASA space shuttles. The Explosion of the Ariane 5 was because of a software bug. There are lessons for us software engineers/teams in these articles, especially in “They Write the Right Stuff”.</description></item><item><title>Xero.com, online accounting, done right</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/xerocom-online-accounting-done-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/xerocom-online-accounting-done-right/</guid><description>Xero is another accounting application that competes with the likes of Quicken and MYOB. It isn't the first application-as-a-service in this market, but it is, IMO the best.
I hate accounting, numbers and tracking invoices and bills. But I don't like paying accountants to do it for me either. However the folk at Xero got everything right in automating an otherwise boring task that you normally pay $1000 of dollar for an accountant to do.</description></item><item><title>Yet Another Reason Why Open Source is Fun! :)</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/yet-another-reason-why-open-source-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/yet-another-reason-why-open-source-fun/</guid><description> This one is from the description of the exhibit module on drupal.org. It made me laugh! :)
Note: This is experimental software meant for advanced users; assume nothing works, and you may be pleasantly surprised. And when it breaks, you get to keep both pieces.</description></item><item><title>Young Hahn Proposes A Rule-Based Drupal Theme Layer</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/young-hahn-proposes-rule-based-drupal-theme-layer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/young-hahn-proposes-rule-based-drupal-theme-layer/</guid><description>While there were many great presentations at DrupalCon DC, Young Hahn's Limitations of the Drupal Theme Layer was the only one that blew me away. Most of the session attendees and readers of the related blog post seem to miss his main point; a proposal for a rule-based theme layer.
read more</description></item><item><title>Your Drupal website has a backdoor</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/blog/your-drupal-website-has-backdoor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/blog/your-drupal-website-has-backdoor/</guid><description>I estimate hundreds of thousands of Drupal websites now have backdoors; between ten and ninety percent of all Drupal websites. Automated Drupageddon exploits were in the wild within hours of the announcement. Updating or patching Drupal does not fix backdoors that attackers installed before updating or patching Drupal. Backdoors give attackers admin access and allow arbitrary PHP execution.
If your Drupal 7 (and 8) website is not updated or patched it is most likely compromised.</description></item></channel></rss>