<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2007s on JS.geek.NZ Bevan Rudge</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/</link><description>Recent content in 2007s on JS.geek.NZ Bevan Rudge</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://js.geek.nz/2007/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best Spam Article</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/08/best-spam-article.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/08/best-spam-article.html/</guid><description>Best article on spam I've ever read, in the New Yorker by Michael Spector: http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2007/08/06/070806fa_fact_specter?printable=true</description></item><item><title>Drupal: Easy is hard, hard is easy</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/10/drupal-easy-is-hard-hard-is-easy.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/10/drupal-easy-is-hard-hard-is-easy.html/</guid><description>A thoughtful summary of drupal by a smart client;
The rule of thumb with Drupal is that only the hard stuff is easy. The easy stuff always seems to be hard. We were having a hard time dealing with an extra annoying bug which was frustrating everyone. This was in reference to wanting to put meta tags on a page -- an incredibly simple task in their old static html site, and (understandably) seemingly difficult in the all new super-powered (but sometimes broken) drupal site.</description></item><item><title>iMac won't get touchscreen?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/08/imac-will-never-have-touchscreen.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/08/imac-will-never-have-touchscreen.html/</guid><description>11:25AM: "[You] introduced multitouch on iPhone, what about for the Mac?"
Steve: "Makes sense for the iPhone, not sure it makes sense in the Mac. Classify that as a research project."
From Engadget: Apple's summer Mac product press conference
WTF? How can such usability revolutionists not realize the potential of putting multi-touch technology on the desktop?
Jeff Han's demo publicized this concept over six months ago, Microsoft has already started doing it the wrong way with with Microsoft Surface, and HP bet everyone to the store a few months back.</description></item><item><title>In the beginning was the...</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/06/in-beginning-was.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/06/in-beginning-was.html/</guid><description>In the beginning was the command line.
I've just finished reading this great essay/book. Wow!! What a great read! Highly recommended.
There is an interesting write up at wikipedia that makes more sense AFTER reading the essay/book. And long-winded but also interesting interview on slashdot.</description></item><item><title>Just Cause - Beta launch</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/10/just-cause-beta-launch.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/10/just-cause-beta-launch.html/</guid><description>I've been working on Just Cause for a while and was glad to see it finally launched! I themed this. JUST CAUSE is up and running! We are, as of TODAY, opening our virtual doors and ask you to PLEASE come to http://JustCauseIt.com and JOIN US! As a beta site, you can still expect some glitches and missing features, but you can help us fix them, by sending us any and all feedback.</description></item><item><title>Just Cause It hype</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/just-cause-it-hype.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/just-cause-it-hype.html/</guid><description>There has been a lot of hype building up around Just Cause recently;
It got a great write up on KillerStartups: "JustCauseIt is a social network with a philanthropic twist. Like Idealist, JustCauseIt lets you connect with other users who are troubled by the current state of the world and wish to spearhead positive changes for society."
Gregory has been blogging about it on the CivicActions blog:</description></item><item><title>MusicIP Mixer</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/musicip-mixer.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/musicip-mixer.html/</guid><description>I heard about MusicIP through a colleague recently, whose description sums it up quite well:
MusicIP Mixer - this one is closed source, but free as in beer - this does an acoustic analysis of each track, and creates playlists 'based' on a single track, or a set of tracks (a 'mood') - and awesome way to discover new music you didn't know you have! It is also a really good browser and tagger (it plays through MPD, or any media player you want).</description></item><item><title>Parallels Coherence weirdness</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/parallels-coherence-weirdness.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/parallels-coherence-weirdness.html/</guid><description>Parallels coherence is even better in the newest versions. Each Windows window is an individual application window on the OSX desktop too -- meaning you can have expose for windows too! However the drop shadows are kind of hackish and break usability sometimes. I'm not sure if it was like this in tiger or not -- I upgraded to Leopard recently...</description></item><item><title>Quotient data type</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/09/quotient-data-type.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/09/quotient-data-type.html/</guid><description>I'm a first year computer science student. The programming paper I'm doing at Massey University is (unfortunately) in C#. And that s the language I'll use in the following examples.From what I've understood about basic data types; an integer is a whole number, with no fraction or decimal value, and doubles and floats are numbers with a decimal value. This works well for most common calculations, but sometimes it is more accurate or convenient to store a value as a fraction; a quotient of two integers.</description></item><item><title>Reply from NZ Minister of Education</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/06/reply-from-nz-minister-of-education.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/06/reply-from-nz-minister-of-education.html/</guid><description>A slashdot posting a while back got me writing a couple of letters
and getting involved at the NeoOffice forums. This morning I got a reply signed by Mr Steve Maharey, NZ Minister of Education, himself. Although it has his signature, I suspect that he didn't actually write it -- although he hopefully read my email and the reply.
Things are sounding positive for open source in education in NZ.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering code of conduct</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/09/software-engineering-code-of-conduct.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/09/software-engineering-code-of-conduct.html/</guid><description>This is an answer to a question I wrote for an old 1st year computer science paper in preparation for an exam. I put a fair bit of effort into and thought it was worth sharing. The Question was something a long the lines of "Give your opinions on the following statement; Employers should require software engineers to accept a code of ethics and professional conduct."
Software Engineers, can not be forced and should not be expected to accept any code of ethics or code of professional conduct.</description></item><item><title>User errors; stupid user or ignorant developer?</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/user-errors-stupid-user-or-ignorant.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/user-errors-stupid-user-or-ignorant.html/</guid><description>This one come's from a great article from humanized about usability in floss:
User errors are a sign that the interface is inhumane, not that the users are dumb. To dismiss these errors as signs of user stupidity is to ignore the very information that should be telling you how to improve the design. “The status quo is good enough” is not an attitude that has ever lead to progress.</description></item><item><title>Witness Hub</title><link>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/witness-hub.html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://js.geek.nz/2007/11/witness-hub.html/</guid><description>I was involved in this project. I worked on google maps integration to capture and display geodata for users, videos, events, campaigns and boilt down to the Hub Map. From CivicActions' launch post; Last Wednesday, CivicActions launched the WITNESS Video Hub.
WITNESS uses video and online technologies to open the eyes of the world to human rights violations. In their 15 years, they have mostly helped on-the-ground organizations document human rights violations by providing cameras and support to document these violations.</description></item></channel></rss>